Quit job
（石田(いしだ)将也(しょうや)）
今まで お世話になりました
Thank you for everything.
Get rid of stuff
That'll get you around 30,000 yen in total.
（業者）全部で３万くらいっすね
Bank
Shoya Ishida
Empty the account.
全部 下ろします
Here's your money back
Last day
A Silent Voice
Class 6 - 2
Class
Take your seats, class.
（竹内(たけうち)）みんな席に着け
（竹内）
今日から新しい仲間が増えるぞ
We have a new friend joining us today.
What?
Lucky you, Ishida.
（植野(うえの)直花(なおか)）やったじゃん 石田
女子だって
It's a girl.
So?
興味ね～し
You think I care?
（竹内）いいか？
Listen up.
じゃあ まず 自己紹介して
Okay, introduce yourself.
For Conversations
Nice to meet you.
I'm Shoko Nishimiya.
Through this notebook,
I hope to become good friends with you all.
you need to talk to me.
Through this notebook,
I hope to become good friends with you all.
you need to talk to me.
Through this notebook,
I hope to become good friends with you all.
you need to talk to me.
Through this notebook,
Please use it when
you need to talk to me.
I'm deaf.
（生徒たち）えッ？
ホントに？
I'm deaf.
ウソ…
ウソだろ
I'm deaf.
Holy crap!
ヤッベ！
miya.
Pleased to meet you, Nishimiya.
I'm Miki Kawai.
（川井(かわい)みき）はい よろしくね
There. Nice to meet you.
Hey, can you speak Japanese?
あ～ 西宮(にしみや)さんって
日本語しゃべれるの？
もう 直(なお)ちゃん言い方
Watch your mouth, Nao.
Come again please.
Uh...
えっと… ハハッ
Come again please.
Oh.
（ノートに書く音）
（川井）「何て 呼ばれてるの？」
Do you have a nickname?
I give up! I'm tapping out!
（広瀬(ひろせ)啓祐(けいすけ)）ギブギブギブ！
（将也）どりゃあ～
（川井）
へえ “しょーちゃん”かぁ
Sho, huh?
石田と一緒じゃん
Same as Ishida, then.
しょーちゃんだって
Her nickname's Sho.
（島田(しまだ)一旗(かずき)）いいですねぇ
Nice.
（将也）はあ？　よくねえわ
What? Not nice.
（将也）ど～りゃあ！
（広瀬）あうッ いいい…
（竹内）え～
今から言う所 書いとけ～
Okay, note down the following sections.
20ページから25ページと
32ページの練習問題
Pages 20 through 25,
and the practice problems on page 32.
These will be on the upcoming quiz.
次の小テストの範囲だから
Gimme your notebook.
ノート貸してみ？
（竹内）まず支点
文字のとおり力を支える点な
First up, the fulcrum.
It's the point that supports the lever.
次 力を押さえる所が 力点(りきてん)
Then there's the effort,
force that's applied at one point.
重りを下げたり
置いたりする所が作用点…
Finally, there's the load
that is raised or lowered.
Levers fall under three classes
based on their locations.
テコはこの３つの位置によって
３種類に…
（西宮硝子(しょうこ)）ハァッ
Nishimiya.
西宮さん
あのね まだ早いの
You, uh, went too early.
私が
I'll tell you when to start, okay?
教えて あげるね
Once more, from the top.
（女子生徒）じゃあ もう１回
Forget about winning the choir competition.
これ 合唱コン ヤバくない？
We're screwed.
（女子生徒）負け戦(いくさ)じゃん？
Here's your punishment for being a lameo.
（将也）しょうもないこと言った罰
（広瀬）ぐぁ… 痛(いって)ぇよ フフッ
Ow, that hurts.
痛(いて)え
Ow!
Y'know...
（植野）もうさぁ
I was distracted for half the class again.
私 また
聞きそびれちゃったんだけど
I'll copy my notes for you later.
（川井）あとでコピーしてあげるね
（植野）頼むわ～…
Thanks a bunch.
"I didn't do anything wrong.
So I will never apologize—"
（植野の朗読）「僕は悪くない」
「だから絶対に
ごめんなさいは…」
（竹内）なんだ 植野
その読み方は
You call that a reading, Ueno?
ったく もういい　次
Forget it. Next.
Screw you too, four-eyes.
（植野：小声）クソ眼鏡
Nishimiya.
（竹内）西宮
（川井）ここからだよ
Start from here.
"Qid beig sdubborn aready,"
（硝子）「いーかげんい
いじを はうのあ やめなたーいよ」
「おかあたんは
あきえがおで いうけお」
sai Mom wid an egasberaded loog.
Bud I don inden do abologize.
「あやまうきあ ない」
All right.
（竹内）よし　次 石田
Next, Ishida.
Are you kidding me?
ウソでしょ
（将也）うう～ うえぇ～えええ
（生徒たちがクスクス笑う声）
Take this seriously, Ishida.
石田 ふざけるな
Could you tell me
what you were talking about?
what  you  were talking about?
Could you tell me
Let's leave.
（植野）帰ろ～
Bye bye, Nishimiya.
バイバ～イ 西宮さ～ん
（将也）お前さぁ
You know...
もっと うまくやらねぇと
ウザがられちゃうんじゃねぇの？
You need to be smarter about things,
or people will start to hate you.
What?
何だよ
Frens...
What?
You're gross!
気持ち悪(わり)ぃ！
I'm Kita from the Class for the Deaf.
（喜多(きた)）
「きこえの教室」の喜多です
Have you all heard of sign language?
皆さんは
手話(しゅわ)って知っていますか？
It's a language where you use your hands.
“手で話す”と書いて 手話(しゅわ)
文字どおり
手で おしゃべりするんですよ～
You can have entire conversations
with just hand gestures.
Isn't it amazing?
ステキでしょ～？
（喜多）そこで皆さん
（将也）手話…
How does this sound?
Sign language...
（喜多）硝子ちゃんと
も～っとお話しするために
In order to talk to Shoko lots more,
would you spend three minutes of homeroom
each morning learning sign language?
毎日３分 朝の会を使って
手話を覚えましょう
（植野）先生
Excuse me, ma'am.
Yes?
（喜多）はい？
Isn't writing in her notebook good enough?
（植野）ノートに書くのじゃ
ダメなんですか？
硝子ちゃんは
手話を使ったほうが楽なんですよ
Using sign language would
make things much easier for Shoko.
And it's much easier for me to write.
（植野）私は手話より
書くほうが楽なんですけど
I'll do it.
（佐原(さはら)みよこ）あの…
私 手話 覚えます
I'll learn sign language.
Teach me how to say
"Miyoko Sahara" in sign language.
Ta...
た　あや…
Hada...
Mi...
go...
ko...
へえ～
"Sa."
Keep scoring them brownie points.
ポイント稼ぎ お～つ
（女子生徒１）めっちゃ好き
かっこよすぎ
I love him. He's too cool.
（女子生徒２）だね～
Right?
Oh, he'll be on a TV show next week.
Can't miss it for the world.
（川井）あッ 来週ドラマ出るし
見ないとだよ
Aren't her clothes lame as hell?
あいつ 服ダサくね？
Don't say that, Nao!
（川井）ダメだよ 直(なお)ちゃん
Via this book, the author...
（竹内）
作者は この作品を通して…
実験のあとも二酸化マンガンは…
Even after the experiment,
the manganese dioxide...
（将也）広瀬 お前そっち
Hirose, take that side.
「に～しみや」
"Nishimiya..."
What are you doing, Ishida?
（植野）な～にやってんの 石田
（川井）やめときなよ
Stop that.
（将也）星…
And a star.
You're going too far, man.
石田 やりすぎだって
Really? I think it's just right.
（将也）そお？　こんなもんっしょ
悪い奴～
Bad, bad boy.
（将也）いいじゃん いいじゃん
Who cares?
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Congrats,
Nishimiya!
Sahara went
off somewhere.
Hurray, hurray!
いい感じ～
Looking good!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Congrats,
Nishimiya!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Hurray, hurray!
Sahara went
off somewhere.
Congrats,
Nishimiya!
Yikes, who did this?
（将也）う～わぁ
誰が こんなことしたの？
Congrats,
Nishimiya!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Hurray, hurray!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Hurray, hurray!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Hurray, hurray!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
Teach us
Nishimiya-ese
sometime!
ひ～ど～い
How mean.
I'll wipe it for you, okay?
（将也）私が代わりに
消してあげるね
はいッ
There.
できた
All gone.
Thank you
どういたしまして
You're welcome.
Let's bounce.
行こうぜ
（竹内）縄文時代は…
Back in the Jomon Period...
アハッ…
（竹内）オラ 石田ぁ
Come on, Ishida.
We're in the middle of class.
授業中だろうが
I'm very sorry!
（将也）はい すいません
Where were we, again...
（竹内）え～っと
どこまでだったかな
Right, what kind of houses they lived in.
あ～ どんな家に
住んでたかというと―
They dug holes in the ground and placed pillars in them.
地面に穴を掘って…
（川井）びっくりしたね
Made you jump, huh?
（植野）ねえねえ 西宮さん
Hey, Nishimiya.
これってさ
ホントは聞こえるってこと？
If you're wearing these, can you actually hear?
（川井）あッ だよね
私も思ったぁ
Right. I was wondering that, too.
（植野）ちょっと見せて
Show me for a sec.
Ueno.
（将也）植野～
What is that?
それ何？　貸して
Lemme see.
よッ　うわ 何これ
Ugh, what is this?
汚(き)ったね～！
Gross!
Dumbass!
Did you say something?
pped
I am ripped
Rippest!
Nishimiya the Rippest!
西宮さん… 大丈夫？
Nishimiya, are you all right?
あッ どうしよう…
What do we do?
Nishimiya!
西宮さん…
You overdid it, man.
（島田）お前 やりすぎ
（将也）あ～ マジムカつく
あのクソ眼鏡
That four-eyes really pisses me off.
What? Move.
何？　どいて
邪～魔
You're in the way.
この人 何やってんの？
What is she doing?
Let's go.
帰ろうぜ
I'm sorry.
Yeah, right! If you've got a problem, say it!
（将也）ウソつけ！
文句あんなら言えよ！
Lemme go! You're creeping me out!
離せよ！　キモいんだけど！
（島田）へ～
西宮さん 面白(おもしれ)ぇ
Wow, Nishimiya's funny.
Shoya's all red!
（広瀬）将也 赤くなってんじゃん
（将也）なってねえわ！
I'm not!
Let's go.
（将也）行こうぜ
（島田）マジかよ 西宮さん
フフフッ
Is she for real?
（広瀬）これはヤバいな
She's crazy.
う～わ～
じゃあな 将也
また明日
Later, Shoya.
See you tomorrow.
ハァ ハァ
ハァ…
（校長）え～
今日は皆さんに―
There's something I'd like to discuss with you.
お話ししたいことが
あります
It's about Shoko Nishimiya, who's absent today.
今日 お休みしている
西宮硝子さんのことです
実は昨日 西宮さんのお母さんから
電話がありました
Actually, her mother called yesterday.
In the past five months, eight of Nishimiya's
hearing aids have been lost or broken.
西宮さんの補聴器が
この５か月で８個も紛失
または故障している
Her mother believes she is being bullied at school.
学校で
いじめられているのではないかと
Have any of you spotted any acts of bullying
or harassment toward Nishimiya?
この中で西宮さんに対する
いじめや
それに近いイヤがらせを
目撃した人はいませんか？
（植野）あ…
（校長）補聴器は
Hearing aids are apparently very expensive.
１つ１つが
とても高価な物だそうです
（校長）
これ以上 お父さんお母さんに
迷惑がかかる前に…
Before you end up causing
any more trouble for your parents...
Ishida...
（竹内）石田ぁ
（竹内）なあ
Look, we all know it was you.
お前だろうが
早く立てよ オラッ!!
Stand up already!
Yes, sir!
（将也）はい！
Ueno.
植野ぉ
隣で見てて どうだったぁ？
What'd you think of it all, sitting next to him?
えっ…と…
Er...
He might've messed with her from time to time.
ちょっと からかってた的な…
ことは あったかも
And Shimada?
（竹内）島田は？
（島田）まあ 一応
Well, I did tell him to stop.
僕も やめとけとは
言ったんですけどね
But Shoya didn't listen.
将也 聞かなかったし
ちょっ… 島田！
Wait...
Shimada, you did just as much as me!
お前も一緒にやってたじゃん！
女子なんて
すげぇ悪口 言ってたでしょ
And the girls were badmouthing her all the time!
ねえ！
Right?
Especially Ueno and Kawai.
特に 植野と川井が
You're awful...
（川井）ひどい…
私 そんなことしないよ
I would never do that!
どうして…
Why would you say that?
You're so mean, Ishida!
石田くん ひどいよ
（男子生徒）泣かした～
He made her cry...
For conversations
Huh? Why is this here?
えッ なんで…？
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
For conversations
Nishimiya,
Shoko Class 6-2
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
What were
you talking
about?
Fi
gure it
out
yourself
I'm
sorry.
We left
cau
se
you  were
taking
too
long!
Dumbass
What do we need
to bring
for
class
tomo
rrow?
Compass.
Thank
you.
What did
the teacher
just say?
Dunno.
I
can't
hear
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
（石田美也子(みやこ)）はい　はい
Yes, I understand.
We're really sorry for everything.
本当に ご迷惑を
おかけしてしまって
はい… はい
Yes, of course!
失礼いたします
Goodbye.
Shoya.
（美也子）将也
Hold it, Shoya!
待ちなさい　将也！
Your teacher told me everything, Shoya.
将也
先生から全部 聞いたよ
ちょっと…
Wait, why are you soaking wet?
なんで あんた
そんなに濡(ぬ)れてるのよ
Shut up. I jumped off a bridge like always.
（将也）うっせえな
いつもの飛び込みだよ
Hold on!
（美也子）待ちなさい
Are you causing trouble for others?
誰かに迷惑かけてない？
（将也）知らねえよ
Don't ask me.
（美也子）先生の話 本当なの？
Was it true, what your teacher said?
（将也）ああ 本当だよ！
Yeah, it's true!
We're going to see the Nishimiyas.
（美也子）西宮さんとこ行くから
支度しなさい
Get ready.
Mizuho Bank
（将也）わあッ！
（美也子）しょーちゃん 帰るよ
Let's go home, Sho.
Be a good boy from tomorrow.
明日から いい子にするんだよ
Okay?
（将也）あれ？
Huh?
（竹内）
偉人と呼ばれている人たちは
いろいろな苦労をしていた
They were called "aliens,"
and they had a really hard time.
What are you doing?
何してんの？
Hey, what are you doing to my desk?
なあ 俺の机で何してんの？
What were you doing, you creep?!
何やってたんだよ
気持ち悪(わり)ぃ！
That look again?
また その顔
Drop the goody-two-shoes act!
いい奴ぶってんじゃねえよ！
何だよ
What? If you got something to say, say it!
言いたいこと あんなら言えよ！
いっつも
わけ分かんねぇ顔しやがって
I don't understand that stupid look,
and it pisses me off!
ムカついてんだろ！
Come on, out with it!
なあッ
言えよッ!!
痛(いって)！
What was that for?
何すんだよ！
（将也）何なんだよッ
（硝子）うぁッ
What's with you?
（硝子）が… ぱってゆ
（将也）何？
I'm dryig...
What?
I'm dryig, ju no!
ごえても がんぱってぅ！
What are you saying?!
（将也）何 言ってんだよッ
（硝子）ううう うう…
What the heck?
何だよ！
I don't get it!
分っかんね～よッ！
（硝子）あぁ う～うう…
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
Get lost, Ishida.
How long are you
gonna stick around?
（将也）あいつ
She really pisses me off...
マジ ムカつく
Nishimiya transferred out.
（竹内）西宮さんは転校しました
はいっと
That's that.
おい 昨日の日直 誰だ
Hey, who was on day duty yesterday?
I didn't get the log.
日誌が出てないぞ
And who was on flower duty?
あと花当番 誰だ～？
Sign Language
Class
Hello there, Shoko.
（女性）あら 硝子ちゃん
こんにちは
Nishimiya!
（将也）西宮！
あ… あの 覚えてる？
U-Uh...
Remember me?
俺 小６ん時の
From sixth grade.
Shoya Ishida.
石田将也なんだけど…
（将也）えッ？　西宮？
Nishimiya?
Wait!
待って！
（将也）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Nishimiya!
西宮！
（走ってくる足音）
（将也）ハァ ハァ…
あれ？
Huh?
Nishimiya!
西宮！
Hey.
え～っと…
Uh...
Oh.
Shoko Nishimiya, Class 6-2
For Conversations
I came to give this back.
これ 渡しにきた
For Conversations
Shoko Nishimiya, Class 6-2
あの…
You forgot this.
忘れ物
“手話 どうして？”って…
Why I know sign language?
I learned it.
覚えた
Anyway, here.
あ… てか これ
Though you might not want to see it.
あんまし
見たくないかもだけど…
あ… あのさ
Hey...
Me and you...
俺と
西宮
友達に
Could we be friends?
なれるかな
へッ？　何言ってんの 俺…
What am I saying?
って 言ってたんだろ？
小学生の時
Wait, she was saying the same thing
back in grade school.
I finally understand what she meant.
やっと意味 分かった
Don't cry.
泣かないでよ
Please don't cry, Nishimiya.
泣かないでよ 西宮
Could you be friends with me?
（将也：こもった声）僕と
友達に なってくれませんか？
...!
（石田マリア）しょーたーん！
しょーたーん！
...!
しょーたーん 起きなさ～い
Sho!
Wake up!
（マリア）朝ごは～ん！
Breakfast time!
（美也子）しょーちゃーん
起きなさ～い！
Wake up, Sho!
Morning, Maria.
（将也）マリア おはよ～
Sho's up!
（マリア）しょーたん起きた～
I'm off.
（将也の姉）いってきま～す
Goodbye, Mommy.
（マリア）ママ いってらっしゃ～い
（美也子）いってらっしゃい
Have a nice day.
はい しょーちゃん
Here you go, Sho.
Thanks for the food.
いただきま～す
Eat up.
（美也子）たくさん食べな
What're you grinning for?
何 そんな
ニヤニヤしてんだよ
I mean...
エヘッ
だってさぁ
Here's your money back
ンフ～
You worked hard at your part-time job, huh?
バイト 頑張ったんだね
You even sold off your manga, clothes, and bed.
漫画も服も
布団まで売っちゃって
But it really made me happy.
でも あんたの
その気持ちがうれしい
By the way, Sho...
ところでさ しょーちゃん
Why'd you want to kill yourself?
なんで死のうとしたの？
W-Well, a lot happened...
あッ いや まあ
これでも
いろいろ あったんだよ
But, uh, I won't...
でも 何ていうか もう…
（美也子）やっぱり…
I knew it.
So I was right!
やっぱり そうだったのねッ!?
I knew something was off!
おかしいと思ってたのよッ!!
Your room was way too clean!
部屋は異常にキレイだし
携帯は つながってないし！
Your phone was off!
And what was with that ominous calendar?!
おまけに何!?
あの意味深(いみしん)すぎるカレンダー!!
４月からあとが ちぎれてて…
All the pages were ripped off from April...
If you don't promise not to kill yourself,
I'll burn this up.
死ぬのやめるって言わなきゃ
これ 燃やすわよ
I'll burn the 1.7 million yen
you shed blood, sweat, and tears to earn!
あんたが汗水 垂らして稼いだ
170万！
Hey! You listening to me?
（美也子）おいッ！
聞いてんのか コラ！
Oh...
何 バカなことを…
Don't be stupid.
（美也子）バカは あんたよ
この親不孝者！
Right back at you, you stupid son!
（将也）あッ ちょ ちょ… あの
Uh... I'm sorry!
ごめん！
マジで すいません
I'm truly sorry!
I won't do it!
やめます
やめます すいません！
マジで！
Sorry, I won't do it! Seriously!
What won't you do? Spell it out!
何をやめるだ
はっきり言えッ!!
I won't kill myself!
（将也）死ぬのやめます！
死ぬの やめます！
I won't try to kill myself!
本当？
You mean it?
I mean it!
（将也）ホントっす
そう 絶対よ
Good.
It's a promise, okay?
（将也）あッ！　お母さ…
（マリア）あ～ッ
Hey, Mom!
Ow!
アッチ アッチ！
あの…
W-Water!
み み… 水 水 水！
（美也子）あッ… アッチ！
（将也）フン！　フッ
（将也）あぁぁ…
（マリア）ああ！
（将也の声）俺は昨日
I was going to jump off a tall bridge
and die yesterday.
うんと高い橋から飛び降りて
死ぬつもりだった
Going to see Nishimiya was part of it too.
西宮に会いに行ったのも
そのための儀式で
It was the biggest test of courage in my life.
過去最大で最強の度胸試し
But...
（将也の声）だったけど…
Friends...
友達…
うう… 何言っちゃってんだよ
What have I done?
At our middle school entrance ceremony,
I overheard Shimada say...
（将也の声）
中学の入学式で 島田が言った
Stay away from a guy named Shoya Ishida.
（島田）石田将也って奴に
近づかないほうがいいぜ
あいつ
He's a bully.
いじめっ子だから
（将也の声）自分が犯した罪は
そっくりそのまま自分に跳ね返る
I realized that your sins
always come back to bite you,
その罪を背負い
and that I had to bear that cross
and the punishment that came with it.
罰を受ける必要のある人間だと
思い知った
And then...
そして 俺は孤立した
Jerk
I found myself all alone.
（生徒たち）おはよ～
Morning.
（女子生徒）ダメ～ マジで
（男子生徒）宿題 ちゃんとやってきた？
（女子生徒）いや 全然終わんなくて…
（チャイム）
（教師）はい じゃあ
All right, then.
Have this translated by next time.
次の授業までに訳しておくように
（生徒たち）あ～ 腹 減ったぁ
腹 減った
（川井）石田くん
Ishida.
（将也）はい
Yes?
あッ 川井
Kawai.
Have you submitted your math notebook yet?
（川井）
数学のノート 提出まだかな？
Oh, sorry. I forgot.
（将也）ああ ごめん
忘れてた
（川井）そっか
I see.
じゃあ 早く出してね
Better get on that, then.
I will, sorry.
（将也）ああ ごめん
（川井）うん
Great.
（女子生徒）中庭 行く？
Wanna go to the courtyard?
"Ishida's always by himself, huh?
（将也の声）
“石田くんって ああやって
いつも１人で いるんだよねぇ”
He's famous for it. Everyone knows."
“有名だよ　みんな知ってる”
Seriously?
（男子生徒）マジかよ～ ヘヘッ
（将也の声）
“ああ またこっち見てる”
"Oh, he's looking this way again.
“いつも１人で
寂しくないのかなぁ”
Doesn't he get lonely, being all alone all the time?
Will he spend his whole life like that?
“一生 あのまま？”
Why does he even live, then?"
“あいつ なんで生きてんの？”
S-Say...
（将也）あ… あのさ これ
I bought this on release day.
発売日に買った
Crap. Maybe I should stop being a fan.
俺 今日からファンやめるわ
Same.
（広瀬）俺も～
だよな…
Figures.
（生徒たち）あ～ 何だろ？
なんか来てる
It's true!
（女子生徒）ホントだ
え～ ウソウソ
Seriously?
（女子生徒）見える～
（女子生徒）分かんない どこどこ？
（男子生徒）あそこ あそこ
（男子生徒たち）オッケー
当たれ 当たれ
いけいけいけ　いけ！
That hair looks familiar.
（将也の声）あの頭 見たことある
Who was he, again?
誰だっけ…
You know...
（将也の声）っていうか俺
また西宮に
会いに行っていいの？
Can I really go see Nishimiya again?
She said she regularly feeds the carp bread.
鯉(こい)にパンやってるって言ってたし
But man, who do I think I am?
ってか お前みたいな奴が
どの面(つら)下げて…
（永束友宏(ながつかともひろ)）は… んッ
（将也の声）泣かしたお詫びなら
行っていい？
Maybe I could go apologize
for making her cry?
She said she'd be there every Tuesday.
（将也の声）毎週 火曜日にいるって
言ってたなぁ…
Would it be creepy?
キモいかな？
（男子生徒）ちょっ 取れ！
ヘタクソ！
（男子生徒）取れよ！
I'm back.
（将也）ただいま～
Sho...
（美也子）しょーちゃん…
（将也）うわわッ
ぶあ…
You gave me a start.
びっくりしたぁ
何だよ
What is it?
エヘッ
Sorry about this morning.
今朝… ごめんね
しょーちゃんが
必死に稼いだお金
For burning all that money you earned.
燃やしちゃって
（美也子）でもさ
But I wouldn't want the money
you earned in order to die, anyway.
死ぬために稼いだお金なんて
使いたくないよ
Sorry.
ごめん また稼ぐよ
I'll earn it again.
（美也子）まあッ ありがと
My, thank you.
Take your time.
ゆ～っくりで いいからね
You must be starving.
さッ おなか減ったよね？
ごはん ごはん
Come, let's eat.
（マリア）おなか～！
Starving!
Tuesday...
（将也の声）火曜日…
Hey, could you let me borrow your bike?
（男子生徒）なあ
ちょっと チャリ貸してくんね？
（将也の声）俺？
Who, me?
Huh? For what?
は？　一体 何のために
（将也の声）
あッ こないだの人
Oh, it's that guy.
I forgot something.
（男子生徒）忘れ物！
取りに行きてえの
I want to go get it.
What? What the heck?
（永束）は？　何なんですか？
Take your own bike.
ご自身のを
使えばいいじゃないですか
（男子生徒）おい
ねーから頼んでんじゃん！
I'm asking you because I don't have one!
（男子生徒）んんッ
（永束）はッ？　やめてください
Stop it.
（男子生徒）おい 離せよ
Let go, dude.
（永束）ちょっ やめて
Hey, knock it off.
Somebody help!
誰か助けて！
Dude...
Anybody!
誰か～ッ！
（将也）あッ ヤベ
Hey!
Crap!
Help me!
助けてください！
Keep it down!
（男子生徒）うるせえよ お前！
（男子生徒）手ぇ離せって！
Let go!
（将也）あ… あの
（男子生徒）ん？
Uh...
You can take mine.
俺の… 貸すよ
For real?
（男子生徒）
え？　マジ？　神じゃん
You're a god.
I didn't get it back.
（将也の声）パクられていた
And it just had to happen on a Tuesday.
よりによって 今日は火曜日で
やっぱ 会いに行くべきじゃない
ってこと？
Is it a sign that I shouldn't go see her?
別に歩いて
行けないわけじゃないけど
It's not like I can't walk there,
but I feel like the universe
is telling me not to go.
“行くな”と言われてるみたいだ
何か理由…
I need an excuse...
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
Fluffy
New
Bread
Miss Baguette
Discount Coupon
（将也の声）
何か とてもスマートで
I need a really neat, natural-sounding excuse.
ナチュラルな理由が欲しい
ふあぁ！
フゥ… へッ
ふっくら新作パン 割引券？
Discount coupon for some fluffy new bread?
This is it!
これだ！
（将也）に… 西宮さん いますか
I-Is Nishimiya here?
（結絃(ゆづる)）いません
She's not here.
Uh, she's right there.
（将也）いますよね…
She's not.
（結絃）いません
Shoko Nishimiya isn't here.
西宮硝子はいません
Excuse me for asking,
失礼ですが
but are you really friends with her?
あなたは本当に友達ですか
それでは
Goodbye.
何でもないよ
Nothing.
There was just a rat out there.
ネズミがいただけ
すっげ～キモいやつ
A super creepy one.
Don't worry. It's never coming back.
大丈夫だよ　もう来ないから
Friends...
（将也）友達…
What?
えッ なんで？
Why?
There he is.
あッ いた！
Ishida!
石田く～ん！
見てこれ！　見てこれ！
Look at this!
自転車！　君のだよね～？
This is your bike, right?
アッハハ
Good timing!
グッドタイミング～！
（永束）
いや～ 住所 書いてあったから
よかったよ
I'm glad it had your address on it.
これ… どこにあったんだろ
Where did you find it?
Dumped in a paddy field.
（永束）田んぼに乗り捨てられてた
いや めっちゃ捜した～
Man, I had to look everywhere.
よかったぁ 取り返せて
I'm glad I got it back for you, though.
（将也）ハァ…！
アッハ
What's wrong, Ishida?
石田くん どうしたの？
Oh, uh...
あ いや… えっと
What's your name?
君の名前…
ガ～ン！　永束だよぉ
I'm Nagatsuka.
君の後ろの席なのに…
I sit behind you, you know.
あッ あ… そうだ これ
Oh, right. This is good bread.
いいパンだよ 食べる？
永束くん
Want some, Nagatsuka?
（永束）石田く～ん！
Ishida!
石田くんッ
Morning.
おはよう　ハァ ハァ…
あ… おはよ
Morning.
Ishida.
（永束）石田くん
Let's go hang out after school today.
今日 遊びに行こうよ
To mark the start of our friendship.
僕ら 友達になったことだし
Over here, Ishida.
石田くん こっち こっち
アッハハ
（永束）どうかした？　やーしょー
Is something wrong, Yasho?
何でも
N-Nothing.
Wait, Yasho?
や… 「やーしょー」？
Makes us seem like big friends, right?
ビッグフレンド感 出るでしょ？
And? Is something on your mind?
で？　何か悩んでるの？
何でも話してみなよ
俺たち 親友なんだから
Feel free to tell me.
We're best friends.
Say, Nagatsuka...
永束くん あのさ
友達… の定義って何だろ
What are friends, anyway?
何ていうか ほら
You know, does one need to fulfill
any requirements to be a friend?
友達になる権利とか
資格とか そういうのって…
Look, Yasho.
（永束）ねえ やーしょー
Hold out your hand.
手のひら 出して
（永束）ほい ほい
And that is what friends are.
これが友達だよ
俺(おら)ぁさ 石田くん
You see, Ishida...
友情ってのは 言葉や理屈
それらを超えた所にあると思うんだ
I think friendship defies logic or words.
資格？　そんなの要るもんか
And requirements can kiss my ass.
くだらないね
How stupid.
いません
She's not here.
い… いるよね？
Uh, she's right there.
いません
She's not.
え～っと あの 君…
Uh, who are—
I'm Shoko's boyfriend.
（結絃）俺 硝子と
付き合ってるんで
（将也）あ… ヤベ 落ちたわ
Well, that sucks.
For the bread, not me.
あッ 俺じゃないよ
パンのことね
So, huh...
ってか へ… へえ～
あッ 西宮って年下が好きなんだ
Nishimiya likes younger boys?
へえ なんか意外
ハハ…
Wow, that's kinda unexpected.
Here, take the bread, at least.
あ… これ
せっかくなんでパンだけでも
いいパンなんで…
It's good bread.
あの
Look.
自分を満足させるためだけに
来てるなら 帰ってください
If you're here just to make yourself
feel better, please leave.
（結絃）もう いいですか
Are we done here?
Goodbye.
では
Hey, laddy!
おい 少年！
My bud says he wants to see Nishimiya!
俺のダチが
西宮さんに会いたいっつってんだ
（将也）永束くん？
（永束）つべこべ言わずに出せや オラ！
Nagatsuka?
Quit being an ass and bring her out!
永束くん なんでここに…
What are you doing here?
I followed you.
（永束）追ってきた
That's what best friends do, right?
親友にありがちだろ？
アッハ
クソの友達は クソ頭だったな
I guess turds of a feather drop together.
Shithead.
このウンコ野郎
Excuse me? What's your problem?
は？　何なんです？　おたく
I dare you to say that again!
もう１回 言ってみろやぁ～ッ！
（将也）ちょっと 永束くん
Hey, Nagatsuka...
（結絃）ウンコ頭
ウンコ頭 ウンコ頭！
Shithead!
（女性１）ちょっと あれ
（女性２）あら どうしたの？
Hey, look.
What's going on?
（女性１）あれって結絃ちゃん？
Isn't that Yuzuru?
（女性２）やだ ちょっと
ケンカしてるわよ
Oh, no.
They're fighting.
（永束）このチビ！
（将也）永束くん 永束くん
（女性３）あらあら…
Nagatsuka...
Nagatsuka!
（永束）訂正しなさい！
（将也）もうやめよう ね？
Stop it.
Take it back!
Come on, Nagatsuka.
（結絃）臭うし！
（将也）永束くん もういいよ 帰ろう
Forget it. Let's go.
Nagatsuka...
永束く…
Why, you...
（女性２）あらぁ
あなた こないだの
My, if it isn't the boy from the other day.
No, you're wrong...
いえ 違い… ます
永束くん ごめん！
Sorry, Nagatsuka!
Ow!
（永束）痛い痛い痛い痛い…
Crap!
ああッ しまった！
（結絃）クッソ～ 会われた
Damn it, they met.
（永束）やったな 石田くん
I'm happy for you, Ishida.
ん？　おい 少年
Hey, laddy.
Are you peeping at them?
貴様 のぞき見してるだろ
（永束）俺にも見せろ！
（結絃）え～
Let me see!
Hmm?
Ishida's waving his hands around.
石田くん
なんか 手をヒラヒラやってる
（結絃）手話じゃねえの？
Probably using sign language.
（永束）何だって!?
What?
すごいなぁ
石田くんには そんな特技が
Wow.
I never knew he had that skill.
ん？　お前 手話 分かるのか
通訳しろ
Wait, you know sign language?
Interpret for me!
"Who was that shithead?"
（結絃）
“さっきのウンコ頭 誰～？”
“全然 知らない人”
"Don't know him at all."
“え～？　キモ～い”
"What a creep!"
And do it right!
ま･じ･め･に！
Let go.
（結絃）離せよ
Don't fall, laddy.
落ちるなよ 少年
（結絃）“本当は”
"I felt like I shouldn't come see you.
“会っては いけないと思った”
“友達の意味を”
I've spent the past two weeks
thinking about what friendship means.
“この２週間 ずっと考えていた”
“僕が君に”
I was searching for a reason to meet you."
“会う 理由”
“探していた”
Ishida...
石田くん…
"I'm so glad.
“うれしい”
“私も 同じこと”
I was thinking the same thing.
“考えてた”
Funny, right?"
“おかしいね”
えっと…
Er...
あッ 西宮 これ パン
Here, Nishimiya.
Bread. For the carp.
鯉に
Is feeding them fun?
エサやり 楽しい？
Oh, okay.
ああ そっか
Shoko Nishimiya, Class 6-2
For Conversations
え… っと
に… 西宮
Nishimiya, you probably shouldn't look inside.
（硝子）う… う…
（将也）やっぱ それ あんまし
見ないほうが
えッ!?　待って 西宮！
Wait, Nishimiya!
（結絃）えッ… 落ちた
Jumped in...
What's wrong?
どうした!?
石田くんが どうかしたのか？
Did something happen to Ishida?!
おいッ
Hey, laddy!
おい 少年！
Ishida jumped into the river?!
ええッ!?　石田くんが川に！
なんでッ!?
Why?!
Ow!
イテッ
What was that for?
な… 何するんだッ
ハァッ
Ew, what is this?
う～ッ 何これ
ああ… 西宮
Nishimiya.
（硝子）ハァッ
ハァ…
ハァッ
Nishimiya!
（将也）西宮ッ！
（将也）ごめんな
落としちゃって
Sorry I dropped it.
バカだな 硝子は…
Shoko's such a fool.
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
Anyone got the balls to beat me?
#tochihigh #hotguy #cutecats #soothingpics
#beautifulscenery #blossomviewingspots
#foodrecs #idolpics
バ～カ
Serves you right, jerk.
Did you see this?
（女子生徒１）見た？　これ
（女子生徒２）えッ 何これ？
石田くんじゃん
What the heck? Isn't that Ishida?
（生徒たち）ヤバくね？　これ
"See you again"...
（将也）“またね”
いいのか？
Is she really okay with it?
（生徒たち）そういう奴だったの？
マジかよ
Hey...
これ 石田くんだよね？
This is you, right?
この人
This guy.
Wh-What is this?
え… 何これ
Ishida, come to the staff room.
（教師）石田くん
ちょっと職員室に来なさい
Suspension Notice
The following student has failed to
follow the school's code of conduct
in public and has thus been suspended
for a week.
Class 3-B - Shoya Ishida
（将也）「今回 私は
飛び込み禁止とされている」
I recently jumped off of Suimon Bridge
and into the river despite it being banned
「水門橋(すいもんばし)から川へ飛び込み」
「その写真をインターネットで
公開しま…」
and then uploaded a photo of it to the internet...
Shoya!
（将也の姉）将也～
（将也の姉）
ちょっと悪いんだけどさ～ぁ
マリア お迎えに行ってくれない？
Sorry, but could you go pick up Maria?
いや 俺
自宅謹慎中なんですけど
Uh, I'm not allowed to go out
while I'm suspended.
（将也の姉）
ちょっとぐらい いいよ
よろしくね
Come on, you can go for a bit.
Thanks.
Wai—
おい…
Hey...
（町に流れる
５時の時報）
マリア～ そろそろ帰るぞ～
Time to go home, Maria.
Sho!
（マリア）しょーたーん！
何かいる～
Someone's inside!
（将也）痛(いて)て…
お おい
Hey...
（体を揺する音）
（将也）おい 大丈夫か？
Hey!
You okay?
Aren't you Nishimiya's boyfriend?
（将也）お前… 西宮の彼氏だろ
風邪ひくぞ
You'll catch a cold.
Oh, it's the rat.
おう ネズミじゃないか
何してんの？　こんなとこで
What are you doing here?
靴は？
Where are your shoes?
Aren't you mad?
怒らないの？
何を
About what?
I was the one who tweeted that pic of you.
（結絃）
ネットにお前の画像 上げたの
俺なんだけど
ああ あれ お前？
Oh, that was you?
そっかぁ～
Boy, am I ever glad it was you.
よかったわ お前で
（結絃）は？　何それ
What the heck?
理由は何となく分かるし うん
I mean, I can kinda guess why you did it.
怒れよ
Yell at me, dude.
（将也）いや 無理だよ
Nah, I can't.
I had it coming.
元は 俺が悪いんだし
（マリア）しょーたん！
Sho!
I'm hungry!
おなか すいた～
は～い
Coming.
I'll be going, then.
じゃあ 俺 帰るわ
You should go home soon too.
お前も早く帰れよ
フッ お前 子供いんのか
You have a daughter?
（頭をぶつける音）
（将也）痛(いて)てて
Ow!
She's my sister's!
姉貴のだよッ
（将也）おい！
Hey!
（美也子）はい 結絃く～ん
Here, Yuzuru.
Eat up.
た～くさん食べなさ～い
（将也）ねえ 姉貴は？
Where's Sis?
（美也子）今日は遅いんだって
Said she'd be late tonight.
（将也）ふ～ん…
（美也子）マリア 熱くない？
Is it too hot, Maria?
（マリア）おいし～い！
（美也子）そ？
It's good!
Great.
（将也）結絃くん 食べないの？
Aren't you eating, Yuzuru?
（美也子）あッ 結絃くん
（結絃）え？
Oh, Yuzuru.
あ～ん
Say "aah"!
どうぞ～
Go ahead.
Damn it...
（結絃）クソォ…
（将也）何してんの？
What are you doing?
急にいないからビビった
That scared me. You suddenly vanished.
ほら 傘
Here, umbrella.
（結絃）んんッ
（将也）ちょ… ちょっと
Just take it.
いいから持てよ
Seriously.
てか 持って
サンキュ
Thanks.
あッ そうだ お前
Oh, you...
（結絃）うえッ!?
（将也）やっぱり
Knew it.
Wanna wear these?
これ履く？
俺が履いてたやつだけど
They're mine, but I don't wear them anymore.
もう履かないし　やるよ
You can have them.
Why'd you run away from home?
お前さ なんで家出(いえで)したの？
I had a fight with Shoko.
ケンカした 硝子と
Huh...
へえ～ やっぱ あれ？
So, like, relationship problems and all that?
つ… 付き合ってると
お互い いろいろある的な
硝子のシャンプー
勝手に使ったから？
I used her shampoo without asking her.
お前なんて要らないって
言われた
She told me go away.
えッ 君ら 同棲(どうせい)してんの？
Wait, you two live together?
傘 自分に差せよ
Hold the umbrella over yourself.
１本しか ねーんでしょ？
We only have the one, right?
いや 本数 間違えたの
俺のミスだし
Well, I should've brought two.
And I can't let you catch a cold,
for Nishimiya's sake.
あと お前に風邪ひかれたら
西宮に悪いし
（結絃）あのさぁ
Man...
何なの お前
偽善者なの？
What is your deal, Mr. Holier-Than-Thou?
Trying to make yourself feel better
by helping a stray?
（結絃）野良ネコ拾って
気持ちよがってんの？
I know you made fun...
面白がってたんでしょ
耳が聞こえないからって
面白がってたでしょ
You made fun of her
because she can't hear, right?
ねえ
で？　今更 手話
覚えたって？
And now you've learned sign language?
何それ
What the heck?
なんか まともな人間にでも
なったつもり？
Think you're a better person now?
You're disgusting.
気持ち悪いんだよ お前
そっか
Oh.
Of course Nishimiya's told you.
そりゃ 聞いてるよな
西宮から
Yeah, that's right.
うん… そう
I'm a terrible human being.
俺 最低な人間だから
I have no right to live.
本当は
生きてちゃマズい奴だから
But at the very least, I don't want to make Nishimiya cry any more.
せめて…
もう 西宮を
泣かせたくないって思っただけで…
ああッ あの 君たちの間を
邪魔するつもりはないから
Oh, I won't try to get between the two of you.
That won't happen.
それは ないから
But this also concerns me...
でも これは
俺自身のことでもあるんだ
（結絃）ここで
This is far enough.
Okay.
（将也）おう
（結絃）あ そうだ
Oh, right.
I'm terribly sorry to burst your bubble,
信じ込んじゃってるとこ
大変 申し訳ないんだけど
but I'm Shoko's...
俺 硝子の…
Now you know.
だから
Little sister?!
妹さん!?
Later.
（将也）あ… ハァッ
あッ 西宮さんのお母さ…
Oh, you're Nishimiya's mother...
Let's go.
（西宮八重子(やえこ)）行くわよ
（結絃）ちょっ
痛(いて)ぇんですけど
Hey, you're hurting me.
すみませんでした…
I'm sorry.
（ドアが開く音）
（結絃）ただいま～
I'm back.
ゆじゅゆ！
Yuduru!
（結絃）わあッ 姉ちゃん…
Sis?
（硝子）
ごめんなたい ごめんなたい
Sowwy! Sowwy!
俺のほうこそ ごめん
I'm sorry too.
あぁ ねえ
I want some of Grandma's perilla juice.
しそジュース飲みたい
ばあちゃんの
Yuzuru, you should stay away from that boy.
（八重子）結絃
あんな子と付き合っちゃダメよ
硝子にも言っといて
Tell Shoko too.
（結絃）そんなの自分で決めるよ
We'll decide that for ourselves,
俺も姉ちゃんも
both Sis and me.
（永束）おお 少年！
Hey, laddy.
元気してるか？　おい
How are you doing?
今日は また どうしたよ？
What brings you here today?
I'm here to return the umbrella I borrowed.
借りた傘 返しにきたんだよ
Wow, laddy.
（永束）おッ 少年
（将也）あッ…
You're pretty responsible.
（永束）なかなか
ちゃんとしてるじゃないか
永束くん
その子 少年じゃないよ
Nagatsuka, that's not a "laddy."
（永束）えッ？
（将也）西宮の妹
She's Nishimiya's little sister.
I knew that all along.
まあ 知ってましたけど？
Thanks for being friends with my Yasho.
いつも俺のやーしょーが
お世話になってます
友達の
This is my friend Nagatsuka.
あ… 俺
You know,
I-I got a cellphone.
携帯 買ってもらったんだ
え～と あ…
You have one too, right?
西宮も携帯 持ってるよな
メ… メールとか やってんの？
D-Do you text your friends and stuff?
友達と？
From your high school?
今の学校の
へえ いいね
Wow, nice.
ほかに
メールしたい相手 いる？
Is there anyone else you'd like to text?
Anyone whose number you'd like to know?
えっと～
メアド 知りたい奴
あッ そう
教えようか？　俺の…
I see. I could tell you...
何？
What?
“さ　は　ら”
Sa... ha... ra?
佐原さんって 小学校の？
Sahara, from grade school?
Yasho, Yasho.
（永束）やーしょー やーしょー
（将也）ん？
So?
佐原さんとやらに
会いに行くのかい？
Will you go see this Sahara?
Oh, come on. It's not like that.
（川井）もう やだぁ
そんなことないよぉ
（真柴(ましば) 智(さとし)）でも川井さんって
しっかりしてると思うけど？
I think you're really responsible, though.
Kawai...?
川井… さん
（永束）やーしょー？
Yasho?
（川井）でも 真柴くんって…
But Mashiba...
（将也）川井さん
Kawai.
（川井）あッ 何？
What is it?
I'd like to ask you something.
聞きたいことが
Remember Sahara from grade school?
Do you know how to contact her?
小学校の時 一緒だった…
佐原さんの連絡先
知ってたりする？
Sahara?
（川井）佐原さん？
Sorry, I have no idea.
ごめん 知らない
But I do know which school she goes to.
あッ でも 学校なら分かるよ
Nao goes there.
直ちゃんが同じだから
"Taiyo Girls' Academy."
（将也）太陽(たいよう)女子学園…
Crap. I'm running low on cash.
わッ 金ヤバ
（永束）石田くん
Ishida, take this.
これを使いたまえよ
（将也）あッ 何これ
そんなに要らないよ
What the heck? I don't need that much.
気にすんな やーしょー
Don't worry about it, Yasho.
交通費 お食事代
ラブホ代と考えたら
You'll need to pay for travel,
food, and a love hotel.
You'd feel a lot better if you had this much.
これくらいあったほうが安心だろ？
（将也）は？
Huh?
（結絃）お～い
Hey!
I brought her.
連れてきたぞ～
Sis was pissed off you were leaving her out
even though she was the one who asked.
姉ちゃんが
自分のことなのに
放置されてクソムカつくって
Sorry, but take her with you, Ishida.
悪いけど
連れていってやってくれ 石田
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
Are you tired?
Yuzuru gave me your number.
Thanks for doing this.
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
I was really happy
when I heard you found Sahara!
hara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
I was really happy
hara!
when I heard you found Sahara!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
about you.
Yuzuru has told me lots about you.
today!
Thanks again for today!
Let's see... We walk from here...
（将也）え～と…
こっから歩いて…
（佐原）しょーちゃん!?
（将也）えッ？
Sho!
うッ う… ご ごめん
S-Sorry.
（佐原）しょーちゃん！
Sho!
ハァ ハァ…
It's me, Sahara!
私 佐原だよ！
Remember me?
覚えてる？
Hey.
Huh? Ishida?
あれ 石田くん？
（佐原）エヘヘッ
Long time no see, huh?
久しぶり
だよね？
I've kept studying sign language.
あれから 勉強 してたの
Wait, is that right?
これ 合ってるのかな？
I left all of a sudden...
途中で いなくなって…
I'm really sorry.
ごめんね
ずっと気になってたんだ
しょーちゃんのこと
I've been worried about you ever since.
I'm really glad to see you again.
会えて うれしい
びっくりした
What a pleasant surprise.
えッ ホント？
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
しょーちゃんは
どんな高校 行ってるの？
Which high school do you go to?
へえ～
Huh...
そういえば
胸元 おっきくなったよね
By the way, your chest has gotten bigger.
何カップだろ？
What's your cup size?
確かめてやるぅ！
Let me check!
（佐原）あ どうしたの？
What's wrong?
I just need to visit the restroom.
（将也）いや ちょっと
トイレ行ってくるわ
Okay, got it.
（佐原）うん 分かった
We're giving out discount coupons!
（女性）割引券で～す どうぞ～
Take one.
We're giving out discount coupons!
（女性）割引券で～す
Ueno?
（将也）植野…
（植野）割引券で～す
We're giving out discount coupons!
どうぞ～
Take one.
Please visit!
（植野）よろしくお願いしま～す
（女性）どうぞ～
Meow
Club
"Meow Meow Club"?
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Sahara here!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Sahara here!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Sahara here!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Sahara here!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
Wow, Ishida.
You learned sign language?
Also, thanks for
helping us get back in touch!
ハァ… すっげぇな 佐原
Sahara's amazing.
I couldn't do the things she does.
俺には無理だわ
Save Video
このノリで 植野も西宮と…
Should I keep going and have
Ueno meet Nishimiya too?
は？　普通に無理なんですけど
What? Not happening.
Yeah, I agree.
俺も そう思うわ～
Meow Meow       Club
（将也）よし
All right.
入ろうか 永束くん
Shall we go in, Nagatsuka?
Onward to Meow Meow Club!
（永束）いざ
にゃんにゃん倶楽部へッ
Welco—
（植野）いらっしゃいま… あッ
（女性店員）いらっしゃいませ～
Welcome!
How long would you like to stay?
お時間どうなされますか？
（将也）い… １時間で
O-One hour, please.
（将也）あ わわ… 割引券 使います
（植野）マジで？
W-W-We have a discount coupon.
Seriously?
（女性店員）は～い
ありがとうございます
Understood. Thank you very much.
ヤバ　ホントに来た
Crap. He really came.
Well, you know...
（将也）何というか まあ…
What exactly were you hoping for?
君は 何を期待していたんだい？
えッ き… 君こそ何を
A-And what about you?
Don't be stupid.
（永束）バカを言ってくれるなよ
I'm only here to meet your friend.
No dirty thoughts whatsoever.
純粋な気持ちで
君の友達に会いに来ただけさ
Right. Your friend...
そッ 君の友達
いるのかい？
Is she here?
正確には 友達じゃないけど
We're not exactly friends...
Elaborate.
とは？
小６の時 いろいろあって
A lot happened in sixth grade.
Things are pretty awkward right now.
実は結構 気まずい…
いないっぽい
I don't see her around.
ふ～ん
（将也･永束）帰ろっか
Shall we leave?
Hearing
Test Room
Bug!
（マリア）虫～！
Oh, you're here?
おう 来てたのか
I came to play with Maria.
マリアと遊びにきた
（将也）あッ これ
西宮 使ったりするかな
Oh, do you think Nishimiya would like this?
Cat!
（マリア）ネコ～！
へえ～
（結絃）姉ちゃん 入るぞ～
I'm coming in, Sis!
Sis?
姉ちゃん…
（結絃）お土産 置いとくね
Gift for you. I'll leave it here.
U...
Ueno?
植野… さん？
Go, go!
Wait, what?
（将也）ちょちょっ… 何？
（植野）久しぶり
Long time no see.
（将也）えッ？　あ…
久しぶり
Oh, yeah.
Long time no see.
Huh?
あれ？　西宮じゃね？
Isn't that Nishimiya?
Still alone, I see.
（植野）相変わらず ボッチなんだ
かわいそ～
The poor thing.
てか 石田
マジで久しぶりじゃね？
Seriously, Ishida. It's been ages.
今度 遊ぼうよッ
Let's hang out sometime.
（将也）は？　いや いいわ
What? I'll pass.
You hate me, don't you?
（植野）石田
私のこと嫌いっしょ？
（将也）ハァ… 別に 何とも
Not really.
I've always felt I should've reached out to you.
私さ
ずっと 石田に
声かければ よかったって
思ってたんだよね
Sorry about grade school.
ごめんね　小学校ん時
（将也）あ 植野 降りて
Oh, Ueno. Get off.
（植野）えッ
うちの店のポーチじゃん
Isn't that a pouch from my workplace?
なんで持ってんの？　怖(こわ)ッ
Why does she have it? Scary.
俺があげた
I gave it to her.
Oh, really?
じゃあな
Later.
は～い
Gotcha.
（将也）え… 植野？
Ueno?
（植野）西宮さん 久しぶりぃ
元気だったぁ？
Long time no see, Nishimiya!
How have you been?
H-Hey!
お… おい！
Huh? You're only wearing one?
何？　１個しかないの？
植野 何やってんだよ
What are you doing, Ueno?
We're gonna have fun throwing it around.
Just like old times.
投げて遊ぶの　昔みたいに
Sorry, Nishimiya.
（将也）ごめん 西宮
No way.
（植野）ウッソ
冗談でしょ 石田ぁ
You're kidding me, Ishida.
えッ？　ちょっと待って
Hang on a sec.
Are you two going out?
あんたたち もしかして
付き合ってんの？
Of course not.
と… 友達だよ
We're friends.
Friends? That's hilarious!
（植野）友達…
何それ ウケる
Friends with the girl you bullied?
いじめてた奴と友達？
なんで
How? Why?
I can't. This is too funny.
無理無理 ヤバ～い
あッ もしかして罪悪感的な？
Is it out of guilt or something?
Nah.
違うよ
You've gotten really lame, Ishida.
石田 ダサくなったわ～
まッ せいぜい
友達ごっこ やってろ～
Well, have fun playing friends.
アハハッ アハハハ
What we were talking about?
“何 話してたか”って？
ん… 何でもないよ
Nothing, really.
じゃあ そろそろ帰るわ
I'll get going, then.
また
See you.
Yuduru.
（硝子）うじゅー
Yeah?
Id monig.
あただお
I'm up. Too surprised to sleep.
起きてる びっくりしすぎて
あたごあん
あやくたべ…
Ead breag—
Wait, wait. Before that...
（結絃）待って待って その前に
What's up?
どうしたの？
姉ちゃん
Sis...
You have your hair in a ponytail today.
今日 ポニーテールじゃん
なんで…
Why...?
う… 変な顔
What a weird face.
（結絃）ヘヘッ
石田に見せてやろ
Ishida needs to see this.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
Massive outbreak of carp today.
Not certain how many people
will come feed them.
Be there.
西み…
Nishimi—
ポニーテール
She's sporting a ponytail?
Ishida, were are you goig?
（硝子）いしだくん どこいくーお
Where I'm going?
“どこ 行くか”って？
パン屋
To the baker's.
Yuzuru asked me to buy some bread for the carp.
結絃に頼まれて　鯉のエサ
もってゆはじゅ
うじゅ たべたかった だけ
We have enough. Yuduru jud waned do eat.
（将也）ちょっ… 西宮
（硝子）いちだくぅ―
Hey, Nishimiya.
You don' have do buy—
かい いかあくて いい
（将也）待って
Wait. Use sign language.
手話 手話
Do I dalk weerd?
わたい おえ えん？
Kinda.
Sorry!
ああ… ごめん！
全然 大丈夫
It's fine, really.
あ～ 俺 行かなきゃ
パン
I-I need to go buy the bread.
See you.
じゃあ また
西宮？
Nishimiya?
（将也）ん？
えッ くれるの？
For me?
Thank you.
ありがとう
Can I open it?
見ていい？
何だろ これ
What the heck are these?
ありがとう
Thanks.
...moo.
（硝子）ちゅき…
What?
えッ？　何？
These?
これ？
...moo.
I lub moo!
Love the moon?
月？
Yeah.
It is very pretty today.
（将也）キレイだね
N-Nishimiya?
に… 西宮？
Yoohoo!
Are you free now?
Let's go watch a movie!
From your big friend Nagatsuka
Say, Nagatsuka.
ねえ 永束くん
これって月に見える？
Do these look like the moon to you?
（永束）んん？
月… には見えないなぁ
The moon? Not really, no.
はッ！　アメ…
Can—
アメじゃないみたい
なんだよなぁ
Doesn't seem like they're candy.
さっき 西宮がくれたんだけど
Nishimiya gave them to me earlier.
マジで何なんだろう…
Seriously, what the heck are these?
Something happen?
何かあったのか？
I told Ishida
I love him.
For real?!
うぇッ？　マジで!?
But it didn't get
through to him.
（真柴）わ～
髪形 変えたんだぁ
Wow, you changed your hairstyle.
（女子生徒１）なんで変えたの？
（女子生徒２）何かあったの？
Why'd you change it?
Did something happen?
（女子生徒１）すごく似合ってる
You look great!
Cut it out, guys.
（川井）ちょっと
やめてよ みんな
朝 時間がなかっただけだよ
I was just running short on time.
（真柴）へ～え
でもそれ いい感じだよ
Really? But it looks nice.
Hey, Kawai.
（将也）あの 川井さん
Why'd you change your hairstyle?
髪形 なんで変えたの？
（川井）え～ なんで？
Why, you ask?
No special reason, really.
特別な理由なんて
ないんだけどな
（将也）へえ…
女の子って そういうもんなんだよ
That's how it goes with girls.
そっか
Oh.
（将也）え… 何？
What?
The other day, Mashiba said
he'd like to be friends with you.
（川井：小声）
この間 真柴くんがね
石田くんと
友達になりたいって言ってたよ
なぜ あなたが
ここにいるのです
Why are you here?
Nice to meet you. I'm Sahara.
（佐原）はじめまして
私 佐原です
（真柴）ども 真柴です
Hello. I'm Mashiba.
（永束）おい やめろ
人の頭の上だぞ！
Stop that!
Don't go over my head!
Long time no see, Miyo!
（川井）
みよちゃん 久しぶりだねぇ
（将也）なあ 今日 西宮は？
Hey, where's Nishimiya today?
（結絃）おなか痛いって帰った
She went home, saying her tummy hurt.
Is she avoiding me?
俺 避けられてんのかな
なんで？
Why?
She was trying her best to tell me something
the other day, and I couldn't get it.
（将也）この間
西宮が
一生懸命 言ってることを
うまく聞き取れなくてさ
（結絃）
姉ちゃん 何て言ったんだ？
What did she say?
月
That she loves the moon.
They're such simple words,
but I couldn't understand them.
（将也）とても簡単な言葉なのに
理解してあげられなかった
Oh, that would've pissed her off.
へえ～
そりゃ ムカついただろうな
まあ 避けられてるかどうか
気になるなら
Well, if you're worried she's avoiding you,
ask her to hang out.
遊びにでも誘ってみれば？
イヤなら断るだろうし
She'll refuse if she doesn't want to see you.
Oh...
そっか
Hey...
A bunch of us are
going out soon.
Wanna come with?
（川井）ハァ ハァ
Let's line up for that one first!
みんな まず あれに並ぶよ
Follow me, and don't fall behind!
はぐれないように
ついて来てね！
Why is she taking charge?
なんで あの女子
仕切ってんの？
（将也）さあ
Beats me.
Ishida.
（結絃）石田
（将也）ん？
あいつ 何？
What's with her?
（結絃）なんか やけに
なれなれしいんだけど
She's acting awfully friendly.
植野… なんで…
Ueno? Why?
硝子の知り合いだっけ？
Someone Shoko knows?
Y-Yeah.
From grade school.
小学生の時の
（結絃）ふ～ん
Can I sit with you, Sahara?
佐原さん ここ いい？
うん どうぞ
Sure. Go ahead.
（川井）怖いかなぁ
（真柴）ん？
I'm kinda scared.
（係員）では準備は
よろしいですか～？
Are you all ready?
Yeah!
（永束たち）イエ～イ！
（係員）
それではスタートで～す！
Here we go, then!
Are you okay with having Ueno around?
佐原さん
植野と大丈夫だったっけ…？
Oh, yeah.
同じ学校で
同じデザイン科なんだよ
We're in the same design course in school.
I learn so much from her artistic sense.
直ちゃんのセンス
勉強になるんだぁ
小学生の頃はさ
怖くて乗れなかったんだ
When I was in grade school,
I was too scared to ride a rollercoaster.
弱虫だったからね
I was a coward, you see.
But I tried changing my perspective a little.
でも 少し
見方 変えてみた
I figured I could decide whether
it was scary or not after I gave it a shot.
怖いかどうかは
乗ってから決めることにしたの
やっぱ まだ怖いけどね
Though I am still terrified.
（佐原）あッ 来るよ
Here it comes.
（佐原）ハアッ
（将也）わわ…
Oh, no!
（佐原）あ～ッ 大変 大変
Your legs are all wobbly, Sho.
しょーちゃん
脚 カクカクだよ
（将也）ん… 大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Wow.
すごいな 手話できるんだ？
（永束）あッ
You know sign language?
手話 頑張ったんだね 石田くん
You must've worked hard to pick it up, Ishida.
（永束）おい！　この手は君のかッ
Hey! What's with your hand?
You're being rude to my Yasho!
俺のやーしょーに 失礼な奴だな
What? I'm just trying to be friendly.
（真柴）え？
普通に仲よくしたいんだけど
No way! Don't think it's that easy!
（永束）ダメだ 甘ったれるな！
もう 永束くん ウケるぅ
You're funny, Nagatsuka.
Anyone who wants to approach Yasho
has to go through me!
（永束）
やーしょーに近づくには
俺の許可が要るから！
（真柴）永束くんの頭
それ本物？
Is your hair natural?
（川井）キャハハッ
（永束）やッ やめろ～！
Stop it!
（真柴）ハハッ
（永束）おいッ ちょっと… 触るな
Don't touch me!
Huh?
あれ？
（川井）真柴くん 逃げて～！
Run away, Mashiba!
行け～ やーしょー
抜け～！
Go, Yasho! Overtake them!
Huh?
（将也の声）あれ？
（将也の声）いいのか？
Do I have any right to have so much fun?
俺が こんなに楽しんで…
でも これってなんか…
あれっぽい
But this feels kinda like...
（永束）ぐうッ
アハハッ 何やってんの
What are you doing?
（将也の声）ほら 何ていうか…
You know, like a group of friends!
友達っぽい…！
Ishida.
（植野）石田
（将也）ん？
I want takoyaki.
（植野）私 たこ焼き食べたい
一緒に買いに行こ
Let's go buy some.
H-Hey, wait.
（将也）えッ おいおい
ちょ… ちょっと
（男性店員）
たこ焼き お待たせしましたぁ
Here's your takoyaki.
どうも
Thank you.
Look, Ueno.
（男性店員）植野さぁ
You don't need to play peacemaker.
こういう おせっかい
要らないから
Die
Go away, traitor
（将也）島… 島田
Sh-Shimada?
Hey, Ishida?
ちょっと 石田？
Sorry! I'll text you!
ごめん またメールする
Ishida!
石田！
Are you mad?
怒ってる？
I'm not.
（将也）怒ってない
怒っては ない
I'm not mad.
（植野）私
I was just hoping you two
could go back to being friends.
２人が また昔みたいに
仲よくなれたらって
思っただけ
会えば 何とかなるかな～
みたいな？
I figured things would work out if you met.
勝手なことすんなよ
Nobody asked you.
Wait.
あれ？
俺も おんなじことした…
Didn't I do the exact same thing?
You and I are alike.
（植野）石田と私って似てるよね
No, we're not.
（将也）似てない
Yes, we are.
（植野）似てるよ
No, we're not.
（将也）似てない
Hey.
（植野）ねえ
Everything would've been fine and dandy
if it wasn't for Nishimiya, right?
西宮さんが いなければ
みんなハッピーだったよね
（将也）決めつけんなよ
We don't know that.
But I do.
（植野）だって そうでしょ？
If she wasn't around, things wouldn't have
gotten awkward between Sahara and me.
あの人がいなかったら
私と佐原が
気まずくなることもなかったし
And you and Shimada wouldn't have fallen out.
石田と島田の仲が
壊れることもなかった
私 西宮さんが来る前に
戻りたいんだけど…
I want to back to how things were before she came.
（将也）島田と俺は
The thing with Shimada...
俺が勝手に そうしただけだ
It's all on me.
Do you hate me?
（植野）石田 私のこと嫌い？
Probably.
（将也）たぶん
I think I want to ride the Ferris wheel.
（植野）あッ
私 観覧車 乗りたいかも
（将也）は？
（植野）西宮さんと乗ろ～っと
I should take Nishimiya.
（将也）え？　おいッ
Hey.
Nishimiya, ride the Ferris wheel with me.
（植野）西宮さん
私と観覧車 乗ろう
（将也）おい 植野
Wait, Ueno.
Take this with you, Sis.
（結絃）あッ 姉ちゃん
これ持ってってよ
I'm riding the rollercoaster again.
俺 もう１回
ジェットコースター乗るからさ
Oh, hey. Welcome, Yuzuru.
（美也子）あッ
結絃ちゃん いらっしゃい
将也なら上にいるわよ
Shoya's upstairs.
Hey.
I got my hands on some top-secret footage.
極秘映像を入手した
Video of the Ferris wheel?
（将也）観覧車の映像？
（結絃）そう
Yeah.
What? How?
（将也）え？　どういうこと？
（結絃）盗撮
（将也）えッ!?
Secretly filmed them.
Listen.
（植野）あのね 私
あんたのことが嫌い
I hate you.
（植野）それは やめよ
Let's not.
I'll talk slowly so you can understand,
あんたが分かるように
ゆっくりしゃべるし
and I'll pay attention to what you're saying.
あんたの声も
ちゃんと聞くから
小学校の時さ
Back in grade school,
I had no understanding of you or your situation.
私は あなたへの理解が
足りてなかった
But you never tried to understand me, either.
でも あなたも私のこと
理解しようとしてなかったよね
That's why you'd obliviously
hand over your stupid notebook,
だから 空気も読まずに
変なノート渡して
and have a stupid smile on your face all the time.
いつも ヘラヘラして
And anytime something happened,
you'd immediately apologize.
何かあったらすぐ
“ごめんなさい”って
So I changed my approach.
だから私 やり方 変えたの
I ignored you and badmouthed you.
あなたのこと無視したり
悪口も言った
They were signs to stay away from me.
“もう近づかないで～”っていう
サインだよ
なのに
But instead of picking up on them,
you fired back.
あなたは それを理解もしないで
やり返した
You went crying to the adults.
大人たちにチクってね
Because of that, Ishida lost all his friends.
そのせいで
石田は友達をなくしたの
Everything around us fell apart.
私たちの周りの
いろんなものが壊れた
I'm sowwy.
（硝子）ごめんなた…
It's not like I want you to apologize.
（植野）別に私は
謝ってほしいわけじゃないの
あの頃は お互い必死だったし
We were doing everything we could back then,
and looking back, I even feel like maybe
it was inevitable how things turned out.
今 思えば
しかたなかったことかな とも思う
But I'm not about to tell you
we should be friends now.
でも今更 仲よくしましょうなんて
話をするつもりはない
I still hate you,
今でも私は あんたが嫌いだし
and you hate me.
あんたも私が嫌い
So how about we take it easy from now on?
だからね これからは
穏やかにいかない？
Let's shake hands as two people
who hate each other.
嫌いな者同士さ　握手
Y-You're wrog.
（硝子）ち… ちがいまちゅ
I hade mysel.
わたちは
わたちが きらいでつ
What the heck?
（植野）何それ
What the hell is up with that?
何だよ それ
で？　だから？
So what?
Are you going to apologize again?
で また“ごめんなさい”？
In the end, things are the same as five years ago.
結局さ
あんたは ５年前も今も
私と話す気がないのよッ
You're not even trying to talk to me.
（結絃）どう思う？
What do you think?
Oh, uh...
I want Nishimiya to come to love herself.
西宮には
西宮のこと
好きになってもらいたいよ
Ueno, was it?
（真柴）植野さん だっけ？
What about her?
（将也）ああ 植野
Did something happen
between her and Nishimiya?
あの人 西宮さんと
何かあったの？
Huh? Why do you ask?
（将也）え？　なんで？
Kawai said things were complicated
in grade school.
（真柴）小学生の頃
いろいろあったって 川井さんが
Nishimiya really can't hear, huh?
西宮さんってさ
本当に耳 聞こえないんだね
Yeah.
あッ もしかして
Wait, is that why she was bullied?
それが原因で
いじめられてた… とか？
許せないんだよなぁ 僕
I can't stand stuff like that.
そういうの
Don't you agree, Ishida?
ね？　石田くん
Huh? What do you mean?
（川井）えッ どういうこと？
私が昔のこと言いふらしてるって
言ってるの？
Are you saying I'm going around
telling people about the past?
（将也）ちょ… ちょっと
声が おっきいよ
Ch-Chill. You're being too loud.
You haven't changed one bit.
結局 石田くんは
何も変わってない
（川井）小学校の頃から
ひどいことばっかり
You were and still are a colossal jerk!
What's wrong, Yasho?
（永束）どうした？　やーしょー
川井さん 落ち着いて
Calm down, Kawai.
What're you talking about?
何の話？
Mishiba, Ishida once bullied a girl.
真柴くん 石田くんはね
昔 ある女の子をいじめてたの
What are you saying, Kawai?
何言ってんの 川井さん
そんなこと あるわけ…
That can't be...
ホントのことだもん！
It's true!
か… 川井さんだって悪口を…
You badmouthed her yourself.
私は西宮さんの悪口なんて
言ってない
I never badmouthed Nishimiya.
（真柴）えッ 西宮さんを？
Nishimiya?
That's right! Ishida bullied Nishimiya!
そう
石田くんは
西宮さんをいじめてたの！
You know, I tried to stop him.
私はね 止めたんだよ
石田くんのこと
でも 石田くん
聞いてくれなかった
But he just wouldn't listen.
すごく怖かったの…
It was so scary.
（将也）ハァ…
（永束）やーしょー…
Yasho?
You ok—
（永束）だいじょ…
Sorry, Nagatsuka.
（将也）ごめん 永束くん
（永束）やーしょー…
Yasho?
Yasho!
やーしょー！
（将也）オエッ
Yeah, I hate myself too.
（将也の声）俺も 俺が嫌いだ
Oh, Ishida.
（結絃）お～ 石田
Hey.
Something wrong?
（佐原）どうかしたの？
N-Nothing.
ああ… あ 何でもない
ハ… ホントに
Really.
There you are, Ishida!
（永束）いたいた 石田く～ん
I brought your bag.
カバン持ってきたよ～
（植野）どうも
Heya.
Nao?
直ちゃん！
（川井）私が呼んだの
I called her.
Sorry about earlier.
さっきは ごめんなさい
But it was all your fault to begin with.
でも…
本を正せば
石田くんのせいなんだから
Still, Mashiba said I should forgive you
if you apologized to Nishimiya.
だけどね
石田くんが西宮さんに謝ったら
許してあげれば？って
真柴くんが言うから
Wait a second.
（植野）ちょっと待ってよ
That's messed up.
それって おかしいよね
What right do we have to criticize Ishida over it?
その件で 私たちに
石田を責める権利ないでしょ？
たち？
"We"?
You've got it wrong, Nao.
違うよ 直ちゃん
（植野）何が？
Got what wrong?
私と違って
Unlike me, you went out of your way
to bully Nishimiya.
直ちゃんは 積極的に
西宮さんをいじめてた
一緒にしちゃいけないよ
Don't lump me in with you.
（佐原）直ちゃん…
Nao...
Ah.
うん 違う
Yeah.
I'm not like you at all. You just laughed
and fell in line with what I was doing!
まったく違う
笑って同調してただけの
あんたとはね！
Mean!
ひどい！
（植野）どう思う？　佐原
What do you think, Sahara?
（佐原）えッ 私？
You're asking me?
Nao badmouthed you a ton too, Sahara!
（川井）
直ちゃんは 佐原さんの悪口も
いっぱい言ってたんだよ
（植野）ホントのことしか
言ってねえよ！
I was only telling the truth!
Out with it, Sahara.
なあ どうなの？　佐原ッ
I-I...
（佐原）わ… 私は…
I was scared of you both back then.
私は あの頃
２人とも怖かったよ
What? Whose side are you on?
（植野）はあ？
どっちの味方なんだよ
（佐原）どっちの味方でもないよ
Neither of you!
（将也）やめろ
Enough.
It's all my fault.
俺が… 全部 悪いから
（植野）その理屈は嫌い
I hate that line of thinking.
Ueno.
（将也）植野
Stop thinking you can decide everything for others.
自分勝手に
何でもかんでも決めつけんなよ
（佐原）石田くん そんな言い方…
You don't have to put it like that.
Shut up, Sahara.
（将也）佐原 やめろ
You're just gonna run and regret
your cowardice again, anyway.
どうせ また逃げて
後悔すんだろ
（将也）“弱虫だ”って
（佐原）ハアッ
（川井）
どうしちゃったの？　石田くん
What's gotten into you, Ishida?
Not another word, Kawai.
（将也）川井 しゃべるな
All you've ever cared about is yourself.
昔から お前は
自分が かわいいだけなんだよ
（川井）ハアッ
Yasho...
（永束）やーしょー
I'm on your side, okay.
俺は お前の味方だから
（将也）
俺のこと よく知りもしないくせに
味方とか言ってんじゃねえ
Oh, buzz off. You don't know
the first thing about me.
I've had it! I'm leaving!
（川井）もうイヤ！
私 帰るッ
Yasho...
（永束）やーしょー
大丈夫
俺は気にしてないからな
It's okay.
It doesn't bother me.
Sho.
しょーちゃん
またね
See you.
Sorry, Ishida.
（植野）ごめん 石田
I shouldn't have come.
私 来なきゃよかったな
石田くん ひどすぎるよ
Ishida, you're too awful.
Keep your nose out of it, outsider.
部外者のくせに 口挟(くちはさ)むなよ
And here I thought we were friends.
（真柴）友達になれたと思ってた
（将也）ハァ…
ああ そうだ
Right.
Summer break starts next week.
来週から
夏休みだろ
Wanna go somewhere...
どっか 遊びに…
I
don't care.
Are you
list
ening
to me?!
I'm sorry.
I'msorry.
Yuzu?
（いと）ゆづ
（結絃）ん？
こんな暗くしてると
目ぇ悪くするよ
Your eyes will go bad if you read in the dark.
Here.
Are you still worried about your sister?
ゆづは まだ
姉ちゃんのことが心配なのかい？
Meanwhile, I'm worried about you.
ばあちゃんは 結絃が心配だよ
姉ちゃんのことばっかで
All you care about is your sister.
自分のことは
ちっとも知ろうとしないんだから
You're not at all trying to figure out
who you are as a person.
Like you're any better.
ばあちゃんだって一緒じゃん
You're skipping out on the senior citizen
meets to learn sign language.
老人会も行かないで
手話の勉強ばっかしてさ
I'm doing it for myself, so it doesn't count.
ばあちゃんは自分のために
やってることだから いいんだよ
Then I'm doing it for myself too.
だったら俺も
自分のためにやってることだよ
Is that so?
そうかい？
You're a good girl.
ゆづは いい子だよ
そうかな…
You think?
Mom keeps yelling at me every day.
毎日 お母さんに叱られてばっか
I haven't gone to school in forever, too.
学校だって ずっと行ってない
ゆづは 心がキレイだ
Your heart is pure.
硝子も頑張ってる
Shoko's hanging in there too.
I've been blessed with
truly amazing granddaughters.
ばあちゃんは
ホントにいい孫を持ったよ
まんじゅうも食べな
Have some steamed buns.
I will.
食べる！
ばあちゃん…
Grandma...
Hey, Nishimiya. How are you doing?
（将也）よう 西宮　元気？
I got some really nice bread today.
今日 とても いいパンが
手に入ったんだ
この パンは
This bread...
It's good, like you.
君みたいに いいパンなんだ
So...
だから…
What the heck?
何だ そりゃ
あれ？
Huh?
Isn't she coming today?
今日は来ないのかな
えっと
Er...
Do you have another stomach ache?
「また おなか痛いの？」
Wait, that's weird.
いや 変か
Hey, Yuzu—
お～い　ゆづ…
Guess I'll go home.
（将也）帰るか
Ishida.
（結絃）石田
（将也）あッ
（結絃）よう！
Heya.
What's with that outfit?
（将也）何 その格好
It's a uniform, obviously.
（結絃）何って制服じゃん
どうでい？　どうでい？
How do I look?
Why?
（将也）なんで？
School, duh.
（結絃）学校だよ！
ていッ
Aren't we on summer break right now?
（将也）え…
今 夏休みじゃないの？
Seriously, what's up?
（将也）どうしたの？　マジで
Nothing.
どうもしないよ
If I had to say, I'm in cosplay.
あえて言うなら コスプレ？
姉ちゃんからだ
俺 行かねぇと
It's from Sis. Gotta go.
I'll walk you. Where to?
（将也）送るよ　どこ？
You don't have to.
（結絃）えッ いいって
（将也）送る
Let me.
Really, you don't have to.
（結絃）ホントにいいって
I saw you crying earlier.
（将也）泣いてただろ さっき
Why?
なんで？
（結絃）石田には関係ないことだよ
It doesn't have anything to do with you.
It does, or so I'd like to think.
（将也）関係ある
…と思いたい
And why is that?
（結絃）なんで
Because I'm worried about you.
（将也）結絃が心配だから
うちの ばあちゃんみたいなこと
言うなよ
Don't start talking like my grandma.
Do whatever you want.
勝手にすれば
Thanks, Ishida.
（結絃）ありがと 石田
I'll be fine from here.
ここまでで いいよ
Ito Nishimiya Funeral
Later.
Hang in there, Yuzuru.
頑張れ 結絃
（結絃）石田
Ishida.
I'm still scared.
やっぱ 怖い
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tom
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomo
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomo
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomo
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomo
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomor
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomor
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorr
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorr
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorro
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorro
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
Hey, Nishimiya.
Would you like to go
somewhere tomorrow?
わッ すげぇ
Awesome!
Let's go check it out.
西宮 行ってみようぜ
（将也）西宮？
Nishimiya?
えッ？　うわわ…
アハハ… ビビったぁ
That scared me.
え？　なんで謝んの？
Why are you apologizing?
Of course not!
そんなわけねえじゃん！
Say, let's hang out tomorrow too.
なあ 西宮 明日は？
明日も遊ぼう
Okay, Nishimiya?
な？　西宮
She said I'd end up unhappy if I was with her.
（将也の声）西宮は
“私と一緒にいると不幸になる”
と言った
This, to the root cause of her unhappiness.
西宮を不幸にしたのは…
俺なのに
I wanna see the ocean.
I wanna love people.
Even monsters have hearts...
ハァ…
取り返しつく気がしない
I don't feel like I can ever fix this.
（将也）西宮～！
おう 今日は結絃も一緒だな
Hey, Nishimiya!
Oh, Yuzuru's coming today? Great!
よしッ 映画でも行くか
Shall we go watch a movie?
ハハハハ 面白(おもしれ)ぇなぁ！
This is great!
Hey.
よッ 来ちゃったぜ
I'm here.
いや～
今年の夏休みは楽しいな
Man, best summer break ever!
な？　結絃
Right, Yuzuru?
（結絃）知らねえよ
Don't ask me.
いや すっげぇ充実感だわ マジで
I'm really enjoying my time, seriously.
Hey, Nishimiya.
あッ なぁ 西宮
明日は どこ行く？
Where are we going tomorrow?
We should totally go somewhere.
明日も どっか行こう
Not tomorrow. We have plans.
ダメだよ 明日は
予定ある
何？
What?
Are you crazy?!
ええ!?　正気かよ 姉ちゃん
What are you making?
何 作んの？
Are you sure about this?
いいの？　これ
Should I really be here?
俺が ここにいんの
合ってる？
石田には 俺たちの母親の
Your mission is to help us bake
a birthday cake for our mother.
誕生日ケーキを作る任務が
課せられた
A-Are you really, really sure?
だ… 大丈夫なのか？
Won't I get slapped again?
またビンタされない？
Uh, forget slapped. You might get killed.
（結絃）いや それどころか
殺されるかもな
（将也）お～い…
Hey...
That looks great!
（将也･結絃）おおッ うまそ～！
What are you doing?
何してるの？
なんで この子がいるの
Why is this boy here, Shoko?
硝子 あなた 何のつもりなの？
What are you trying to pull?
Get out.
There, there, Mom.
（八重子）帰りなさ…
（結絃）まあまあまあ お母さん
（結絃）いいじゃん
おめでたい日なんだからさ
What's the big deal? It's a happy occasion.
Yuzuru.
結絃…
You look good.
（結絃）似合ってるよ
（将也）ハア…
Yum!
（結絃）うまッ
Looks like you avoided getting killed, Ishida.
何とか殺されなくて済んだな 石田
Y-Yeah.
（結絃）やったな 姉ちゃん
We did it, Sis.
（八重子）そういえば 結絃
By the way, Yuzuru.
県のコンクールに
写真 選んで応募しといたから
I picked a photo and submitted it
to the prefectural photography contest.
Wait, what?
（結絃）え？　何それ
Sho said you should take part.
しょーちゃんが出したいって
What? They're all weird photos.
え～？
趣味悪い写真ばっかだぜ
That's not what I found.
そうでもなかったわよ
（結絃）何だよ ２人して勝手に～
Who asked you two?
（硝子）プフフッ
（結絃）そういえば
次の火曜日 花火大会だぜ 石田
Oh, right.
There's a fireworks show next Tuesday, Ishida.
Nah, I'll pass.
いや 俺はいいよ
行こうぜ
Come on. Let's go.
Will this do?
（将也）ここで いいかな？
（結絃）いい いい
Yeah.
（結絃）あッ
俺 焼きそば買ってくる
Oh, I'll go get some yakisoba.
Come with me, Mom.
ついて来てよ
Thanks.
ありがとう
あッ この間
家に呼んでくれて ありがとう
Oh, and thank you for
inviting me over the other day.
Was your mother...
おばさん…
Yeah. You think she was happy?
喜んでた… かな？
I couldn't tell from her poker face.
基本 無表情だったけど
When is your birthday?
西宮の 誕生日は いつ？
June 7th?
６月
７日
It already passed!
って もう過ぎてるじゃん
そっかぁ
So you're already eighteen, huh?
もう西宮は18歳なんだな
Let's celebrate your nineteenth together, okay?
来年は ちゃんと一緒に
お祝いしような
I went and said "together"!
“一緒に”って言っちゃった
（将也）あッ そっか
Oh, is that so?
なるほどな！
ハハッ　そっか
I see...
あッ どうしたの？
What's up?
え？　花火
まだ終わってないのに？
But the show isn't over yet.
“勉強”…
You need to study?
そっか
Oh, okay.
I'll walk you.
あッ 俺 送るよ
But...
でも…
そっか
All right.
じゃあ　またな
See you.
Huh?
（結絃）あれ？　姉ちゃんは？
Where's Sis?
That reminds me, Ishida.
あッ そうだ 石田
Could you go get my camera for me?
ちょっと カメラ取りに行ってくれ
（ドアを開ける音）
（将也）お邪魔しま～す
Pardon me...
あッ 暗(くら)
Whoa, it's dark.
Nishimiya?
西宮～？　入るぞ～
I'm coming in.
あった あった
There it is.
充電は… あるか？
Is it charged?
あッ こっから花火 見える…
You can see the fireworks from here...?
あ？　西宮 いるじゃん
Oh, she is here.
に… 西宮？
Nishimiya?
西宮？
ちょ ちょ…
ちょっと待って
W-W-Wait a second.
What are you doing, Nishimiya?
何してんの
西宮？
Nishimiya?
（将也）西宮…!?
Nishimiya!
西宮ッ！
西宮…！
Shoko!
硝子～ッ!!
Why...
なんで…
Why, Nishimiya?
なんで　西宮
Nishimiya, grab the ledge!
（将也）西宮 柵ッ
柵 持って ぐッ…
（将也の声）神様…
I beg you, God.
Please give me one last ounce of strength.
どうか もうひと振り
俺に力をください
もう嫌なことから
逃げたりしません
I won't run away from things anymore.
明日から…
From tomorrow,
みんなの顔をちゃんと見ます
I'll look at people's faces.
From tomorrow, I'll listen to their voices.
明日から
みんなの声もちゃんと聞きます
From tomorrow, I promise to do things right.
明日から ちゃんとするから
Nishimiya...
に… 西宮ッ…
I gave her that scar back then.
（将也の声）
ああ あの時 つけた傷
俺 ちゃんと謝ったっけ？
Did I ever actually apologize to her?
Sorry.
ごめん
I'm sorry, Nishimiya.
ごめんな 西宮
まだ怒ってる？
Are you still mad?
Man, I really messed up.
あッ しまったなぁ
I should've asked her how she felt about me.
西宮に
俺のこと どう思ってるのか
聞いとけばよかった
By the way, Nishimiya.
ちなみに西宮　俺はさ…
You see, I...
ふッ！　ぐううッ
あぁぁ～！
Sho.
（美也子：こもった声）
しょーちゃん
Your sister made pancakes.
お姉ちゃんが パンケーキ
焼いてくれたわよ
マリア 花火 見るよ～
I'm gonna see the fireworks!
（将也の声）冷(つめ)た…
So cold...
温(あった)かい…
Yet so warm...
Suimon
Municipal
Hospital
ital
おばさんッ
Auntie!
Oh, Yuzuru.
あら 結絃ちゃん
（結絃）やっと会えた
I finally got to see you.
I called the shop, but nobody answered.
店 電話しても留守だし
And the hospital said no visits.
面会もダメって言われたから
（美也子）
ああ それならもう大丈夫
Oh, you can see him now.
今日から部屋 移動したのよ
They moved him to a ward room today.
Come with me. Let him see your face.
一緒に行きましょ
顔 見せてあげて
You see, Shoko...
（結絃）おばさん あの 硝子…
（八重子）石田さん
Ishida.
西宮さん
Nishimiya?
Uh, I'm very sorry.
あの 西宮さん ごめんなさい
また こんな形で
ご迷惑をおかけして…
We caused you trouble once again.
I'm truly sorry.
（八重子）すみませんでした
（美也子）やめてくださいッ
Please don't!
I'm sure my son did something to Shoko again.
きっと息子が また
硝子さんに何かしたんです
Otherwise...
（美也子）じゃなきゃ あんな…
（結絃）おばさん
Auntie, he saved my stupid sister.
（結絃）
石田は うちのバカ姉ちゃんを
助けてくれたんです
I was too negligent.
俺の監督不行き届きです
I'm sorry.
（結絃）ごめんなさい…
（美也子）ハアッ…
Please...
どうか
Please raise your head.
どうか顔を上げてください
I'm just glad Shoko's all right.
硝子ちゃんが無事で何よりです
You too, Yuzuru.
結絃ちゃんも　ね？
お願いだから…
Please, I beg you.
Why did Ishida have to get hurt?!
（植野）なんで石田が
傷つかねえといけねえんだよッ！
Quit trying to be some tragic heroine!
悲劇のヒロイン
ぶってんじゃねえぞッ！
何か言えよ
Say something.
“私は みんなに迷惑かけて
とっても傷ついたので”
"I caused everyone trouble
and was really hurt by it,
“自殺しようと思いました”
so I tried to commit suicide.
“ごめんなさい”か？
I'm sorry," huh?
Who the hell do you think you are?
とんだ思い上がりなんだよッ！
おい 西宮
You're a cancer, Nishimiya.
お前 マジ害悪(がいあく)なんだよ
あんたみたいに
テメェの頭ん中でしか
People like you, who can only see things
from their own point of view,
物事 考えられねえような奴が
piss me off the most!
いっちばん腹立つんだよッ
（植野）痛(いって)え
And who the hell are you?!
お前 誰だよッ
Are you her mother?!
お前 西宮の母親か？
（結絃）やめ…
（植野）ちゃんと世話できねえんだったら
Stop...
Don't have kids if you can't take care of them!
ガキなんて産むんじゃねえよッ！
（美也子）何やってるの
What are you doing?
Stop it.
やめなさい
やめなさいッ
Stop it!
なんで！
Why?
何してるのよ…
What is wrong with you two?
ハァ ハァ…
（美也子）硝子… さん？
Are you Shoko?
Soww...
（硝子）うう… ごめ…
I'm sowwy...
ごめんなた…
ごめんなたいッ
I'm so sowwy!
ごめんなたい！
（硝子）ごめん… なたい！
What are you doing?
（八重子）何してるの？
I used to think Sis would stop talking about
wanting to die if she saw these.
（結絃）これ見たら
姉ちゃん 死にたいなんて
言わなくなると思った
What was I supposed to do?
（結絃）どうすれば よかったの？
（永束）ふんッ 開(あ)っかねえ
It's not opening.
押さえてやがる
She's holding it shut!
Oh, didn't see you there, Nishimiya.
あ 西宮さん いたの？
Shall we head someplace else?
I'll get you a drink.
あっち行かない？
ジュース 奢(おご)っし
I heard about what happened with Yasho.
（永束）
やーしょーとのこと聞いたよ
I destroyed everything
Ishida had built up
You mean what happened at the bridge?
それって橋でのこと？
Yasho accepted a weirdo like me.
やーしょーはさ
俺みたいな奴
受け入れてくれたんだ
He made me realize for the first time
what a best friend was.
親友って こういうものなんだって
初めて知ったよ
Yasho's my big friend,
so I really need him to wake up.
やーしょーは
僕のビッグフレンドだから
目を覚ましてもらわなきゃ困る
I want to fix what I destroyed
（川井）つらいから死ぬなんて
どうかしてるッ！
Trying to kill yourself 'cause
you're having a hard time is messed up!
Kawai, you're being too loud.
川井さん 声がデカいよ
（川井）大きい声 出さないと
聞こえないの 西宮さんには！
She won't hear me unless I yell!
ハアッ
We were so worried!
みんな 心配してたのよ…
Everyone goes through difficulties in life.
誰だって
生きてればツラいこともあるの
But we're all in the same boat, aren't we?
でも みんな そうでしょ？
You have to learn to love even the things
you hate about yourself and move forward.
だから…
自分のダメな所も
愛して前に進んでいかなくちゃ
I'm glad you're all right.
無事でよかったね
I want to fix what I destroyed
I see.
（佐原）そっか
みんなの所 行ってきたんだ
You went and saw everyone, huh?
すごいね
You're strong.
I'm not as strong as you.
私 自信ないよ
もし 石田くんが目覚めても
Even when Ishida does wake up,
I won't know how to face him.
私 合わせる顔がない
私は 変われなかった
I couldn't change.
I failed to protect you again!
しょーちゃんのこと
また守れなかった
I'm still the same old coward.
弱虫のまま
You gan jange from now,
こえから かある
Tahada...
しゃはらたん
Thank you for coming, Sho.
（佐原）来てくれてありがとう
しょーちゃん
（将也：こもった声）わッ！
（硝子）もう やめてよね
Jeez, cut that out.
Nishimiya.
Found you.
How are you doing?
You know,
this is kinda weird, huh?
I...
wanted to die...
Oh.
Tuesday will be over soon.
Later,
Nishimiya.
（硝子）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
う… ハァ ううッ
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
ハッ　にひみや…
Nihimiya!
What's all this?
あに これ？
おはーひゃん？
Mom?
Get this crap off me!
こえ…
こえ とってッ
ハァ… 西宮…
Nishimiya...
ハァ ハァ…
Nishimiya.
西宮…
Nishimiya...
西宮… ハァ…
西宮
ハアッ
Hey.
（硝子）ハアッ
プハッ
ア～ハハハハ
えッ 大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Great.
I'm glad you're fine.
よかった
無事で
西宮
Nishimiya,
I'm all good now.
俺 もう元気だよ
More or less.
大体は
Come on. Don't cry.
そんな顔しないでよ
西宮
Oh, right.
あ そうだ
Nishimiya,
西宮さん
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
I hadn't actually apologized to you
for what I did to you in the past.
昔のこと ちゃんと
謝ってなかったから
Or everything after that, either.
あと そのあとのこととかも
いっぱい
I'd probably created a convenient
image of you in my head.
俺さ
たぶん 君のこと
都合よく 解釈してた
I wanted to talk to you more.
もっと
話がしたかったんだ
君と
That was probably all.
たぶん　それだけ
But I hurt you
なのに俺は 君を傷つけて
and forced you into making
the worst possible choice.
結果 最悪な選択させちゃって
No!
（硝子）ちあう…
You fell becas I couldn jange!
わだぢが
かあらなかっだがら
あなだが おちた…
Id all my fauld!
でんぶ…
あだぢの せい
If only I were gone...
わだぢが いだぐなれば
いいっで
I'm so sowwy!
ごめんなたい… うう…
泣かないでよ 西宮
Please don't cry, Nishimiya.
Listen, Nishimiya.
（将也）ねえ 西宮
I was talking to you before coming here.
俺 さっきまで
君と話してた
It was within a dream.
夢ん中で
Looks like I was trying to give up on everything.
諦めようと思ってたみたい
いろいろ
But that wasn't right.
（将也）でも 違った
I'd felt the same way as you forever,
俺も ずっと
西宮と同じこと考えてたけど
but I realized it didn't mean that I deserved to die.
それでも…
やっぱり
死に 値(あたい)することじゃないと
思ったよ
I want to apologize to the others too.
みんなにも
ちゃんと 謝りたい
Hey, Nishimiya. I...
あのさ 西宮
俺…
I want you to help me live.
君に
生きるのを
手伝ってほしい
（硝子）ハアッ…
Nishimiya.
西宮
（将也）ハッ あれッ？
H-Huh?
Did I just do something really creepy?
キ… キモいことやっちゃったな
Crap!
ヤバいッ うわ
ご… ごめんね
忘れて 西宮
S-Sorry! Forget it!
今の 忘れて
Forget what I just said!
We've reached your destination, sir.
（美也子）
お客さ～ん 着きましたよ～
（将也）ふがッ
お～ マリア
お花に水やってたのかぁ
Oh, Maria. You're watering the flowers?
Atta girl.
ハハッ 偉いなぁ
Are you gonna die?!
しぬ～？　しぬ～？
（美也子）マリア
しょーちゃんは生き返ったんだよ～
Maria, Sho came back to life.
死んでないよ～ マリア
I'm not dead, Maria.
（美也子）あら
Isn't that Ueno?
植野さんじゃない？
She nursed you the entire time, you know.
あの子 ず～っと しょーちゃんの
看病してくれてたのよ
お礼 言っときなさい
Go thank her.
お見舞い来てくれてたって…
I hear you came to visit.
I'm a really awful person.
（植野）私さ ダメな奴なんだ
Even in this situation,
I just couldn't bring myself to like Nishimiya.
こんな状態になって やっぱり
余計に 西宮さんのこと
好きになれなくてさ
Guess I don't have to.
ならなくても いいのか…
Oh, Shimada and Hirose were the ones
who pulled you up when you fell.
あッ 石田が落ちた時
あんたのこと引っ張り上げたの
島田たちだから
They asked me not to tell you,
but screw that.
黙っとけって言われたけど
石田
Ishida...
Welcome back.
おかえり
Well, I'm out.
じゃ 帰るわ
（将也）ありがとう
Thank you.
（八重子）
やだ ちょっと切りすぎよ
Gosh. You've cut it too short!
これくらいのほうが
かわいいわよ～
This suits you much better.
Oh, welcome back, Sho.
あッ しょーちゃん おかえり
Thanks for having me.
（八重子）お邪魔してます
W-Welcome.
あ… い… いらっしゃいませ
Ishida.
（八重子）石田くん
（将也）はい！
Yes?
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
Oh, no...
（将也）あ いや… こちらこそ
I'm sorry too.
That's right. My son is invincible.
そうよ～ うちのは無敵だから
（ペドロ）オカサ～ン
マリア 迎エニ 行ッテクル
Moms!
I'll go pick up Maria.
Sure.
（美也子）は～い
（八重子）誰!?
Who is that?
（美也子）
上の子の旦那 帰ってきたの
コンニチワ
イラッシャイ
My daughter's husband. He came back.
Hello, and make yourself at home.
Oh, Sho.
あッ しょーちゃん
ゆづちゃん 上に来てるよ
Yuzu's upstairs.
冷蔵庫のゼリー 出してあげて
Give her the jelly in the fridge.
（カーテンを開ける音）
（結絃）よう
Hey.
冬服？　似合ってんじゃん
Winter uniform?
Looks good.
見たまえ 石田
Get a load of this, Ishida.
Photography Contest
Student Prize Winner
Yuzuru Nishimiya (9th grade)
（将也）えッ？
わッ マジかよ すげぇな！
Are you serious? That's crazy!
Photography Contest
Student Prize Winner
Yuzuru Nishimiya (9th grade)
Photography Contest
Student Prize Winner
Yuzuru Nishimiya (9th grade)
Photography Contest
Student Prize Winner
Yuzuru Nishimiya (9th grade)
Photography Contest
Student Prize Winner
Yuzuru Nishimiya (9th grade)
そして これも見たまえ
Get a load of this too.
（将也）わッ マジかよ すげぇな…
Are you serious? That's crazy...
I beg ya, boss!
後生(ごしょう)だ 旦那
俺に勉強を教えておくれよぉ
Please tutor me!
おッ いいぜ
Sure.
学校 行き始めたんだな
You started going to school, huh?
Shoko broke the ice for me.
（結絃）硝子に
きっかけ作ってもらった
Well, I'll give it my best shot.
まあ 何とかやってみるよ
I wanna live up to her expectations.
期待に応えたい
I hear your school festival starts tomorrow?
明日から学祭(がくさい)なんだって？
（将也）ああ そうだよ
Yeah, you heard right.
Everyone was talking about
going to your school's festival tomorrow.
I'll be waiting by the front gates at 10.
Yuzuru and Mom will come later.
Hello
From: Shoko Nishimiya
お… おはよ みんな
M-Morning, guys.
元気だった？
How've you been?
ひどいこと言って
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry I said all those mean things.
ハァ…
よし！
Let's do this!
（将也）いってきます
I'm off.
Take care.
頑張ってね～
（将也）あッ それ
Is that how they're used?
そういうふうに
使うんだったのか
（美也子）何？
What?
Nothing.
（将也）ううん いってきま～す
Later.
Have a nice day!
いってらっしゃ～い
あッ おはよ
Morning.
（将也）行こっか
Shall we?
（女子生徒１）ちょっと見た？
（男子生徒１）あれ 石田じゃね？
Isn't that Ishida?
Who?
（男子生徒２）誰？
（女子生徒２）
入院してた人でしょ？
The one who was hospitalized?
（女子生徒３）あの飛び込みの？
The jumper?
I've never told you this before,
初めて 言うけどさ
but I don't fit in at school.
俺 学校で 浮いてるんだ
I can't look at people's faces.
なんか 人の顔
見れなくてさ
So I feel much better when I look down.
だから 実は
下向いてると 楽
（将也）“下向いてていい”って？
I can keep looking down?
（将也）に… 西宮
N-Nishimiya...
俺 普通に歩く… よ
I can walk just fine.
Thanks, Nishimiya.
（将也）ありがとう 西宮
俺のクラス ここ
This is my class.
（女子生徒１）お湯って沸いた～？
Is the water ready?
（女子生徒２）あと ちょっと
Gimme a bit more.
（女子生徒１）石田くん？
石田くんじゃん！
Ishida?
It's Ishida!
（男子生徒）わあ もう大丈夫なの？
（将也）ヘヘヘ…
Are you okay now?
Nishimiya...
西宮
I think my tummy hurts.
俺 ちょっと おなか痛いかも
ごめん
Sorry.
やーしょー！
Yasho!
あれ？
（永束）やーしょー？
Yasho?
Nagatsuka?
永束… くん？
（永束）やーしょー
おなかが痛いの？
Yasho, do you have a stomach ache?
（永束）やーしょー
Yasho...
やあ 永束くん
おはよう 元気だった？
Hey, Nagatsuka. Morning.
How're you doing?
The other day—
（将也）この間は…
（永束）やーしょー
Why are you looking down?
（永束）なんで下 向いてるの？
Huh? That's weird.
（将也）あれ？　おかしいな
本当は ちゃんと
顔合わせるつもりで来たんだけどな
I actually meant to look you straight in the eye.
D-Did I get cold feet?
ビビったかな
Hey, Yasho.
（永束）ねえ やーしょー？
Ishida!
石田くんッ！
I'm so glad you're all right!
よかった 無事で
ぐふッ
君が… ううッ
If you...
（将也）えッ…
（永束）君があのまま目を覚まさなかったら
If you hadn't woken up,
it would've been all over for me!
僕の全てが
終わってしまうところだった…！
やーしょー
Yasho!
Don't worry about what happened on the bridge!
橋の上での… ことは
気にするな
Those things happen in life.
あんなこと
生きてりゃ何度でもあるさ
So please, Yasho...
だから やーしょー
頼むから もう…
遠くへ行かないでくれぇ
Don't go anywhere!
I beg you!
お願いだからぁ…
永束くん…
Nagatsuka...
ごめん
I'm sorry about everything.
ホントに たくさん
Also, thank you.
あと
ありがとう
（永束）やーしょー
（将也）あと…
Yasho.
Oh, and...
そのヒゲ どうしたの？
What's with the moustache?
願(がん)かけだよ
君が 早く目覚めるようにって
A prayer so you'd wake up as soon as possible.
永束くん…
Nagatsuka...
あッ どうしたの？
What's up?
I heard Nagatsuka screaming out your name.
（真柴）石田くんの名前を叫んでる
永束くんの声が聞こえたから
そっか
Oh.
Kawai, you should hand them to him.
（真柴）川井さん
石田くんに渡さないと
持ってる？
You got them?
I brought them, but I can't give him those.
They came out really badly.
（川井）う… 持ってきたけど
ダメだよ あんな出来損ない…
（真柴）別にいいじゃないか
渡そう
It's fine. Hand them over.
（川井）これ…
（将也）ん？
Here.
I actually wanted to make
a thousand of these, but I couldn't.
（川井）本当はね
千羽(せんば) 集めたかったんだけど
集まらなくて
I asked everyone, but...
みんなに… 声かけたんだけど
ごめ…
Sorry...
（将也）あ いや… いや
すごいよ！
N-Nah, it's amazing!
これで十分
This is plenty!
I've never got anything like this before,
俺 こんなの もらったことないから
so it makes me really happy.
すごいうれしい マジで
Thank you, Kawai.
ありがとう 川井さん
And I'm sorry.
あと ごめん
You too, Mashiba.
真柴くんも
いや 君はすごいよ
Nah. You're amazing.
Yikes. So gross.
（植野）う～わ キッモ
友情ごっこかよ
鳥肌 立ったわ
Playing friends, are we?
You're making my skin crawl.
（川井）なんで直ちゃんは
そんな言い方するの？
Why do you have to be like that?
は？　何だよ 川井っち
Huh?
What's your problem, Kawai?
You wanna go?
やんのか？
ちょっとちょっと ２人とも
Come on, you two.
あッ 石田くん…
Ishida...
I'm sorry.
ごめんね　石田くん
石田くんが
大変だったっていうのに
You were going through so much,
but I was no help.
まるで変わってない
I haven't changed at all.
そんな…
Come on.
俺だって…
I'm the same.
They're not talking about anything serious.
そんな深刻な話してねえよ
You apologized again.
また謝った
まッ それが あんたか
Well, I guess that's just who you are.
バ～カ
Dumbass.
ハアッ…！
ハアッ
Dumbass.
バ～カッ
プヒヒッ
ああ もう 知らんッ
Oh, forget it.
I'll go get some fried chicken.
から揚げ 食べに行こうっと
（川井）逃げた
She ran away.
（佐原）照れたんだよ
She was too embarrassed.
Listen, I've got a favor to ask of you all.
あのさ
みんなに
お願いがあるんだけど
いいかな？
May I?
I'd like us to check out the festival together.
みんなで一緒に
文化祭 見て回りたい
（女子生徒１）ヤバ～い
めっちゃおいしい
God, this is seriously yummy!
Let's check out the gym next.
（女子生徒２）次 体育館 行こう
（男子生徒１）
よく学校 来れるよな
How can he come to school?
Hey, Class B's stall is seriously great.
（男子生徒２）ちょちょっ…
Ｂ組の店 マジいいよ
（男子生徒３）行く行く！
Count me in.
A
Ko
i
wo
shi
ta
no
wa
A~ reason I fell for you
A
Ko
i
wo
shi
ta
no
wa
Nee
ma
e
mu
i
te
Hey, look ahead
Nee
ma
e
mu
i
te
A
ta
shi
wa
ko
ni
i
ru
de
sho?
I'm right here
A
ta
shi
wa
ko
ni
i
ru
de
sho?
Da
ka
ra
mo
u
na
ka
i
de
So don't cry anymore
Da
ka
ra
mo
u
na
ka
i
Ko
ko
ro
ga
de
wa
re
ta
to
ki
mo
When your heart is broken,
Ko
ko
ro
ga
wa
re
ta
to
To
ki
ku
be
tsu
na
mo
hi
bi
wo
ku
re
ta
I'll be there, for your day to be special
To
ku
be
tsu
na
hi
bi
wo
ku
re
Sa
sa
ta
i
ni
ka
ke
chi
ga
e
ta
a
ka
Red, could conflict for trivial matters
Sa
i
ro
sa
i
ni
ka
ke
chi
ga
e
ta
a
ka
i
ro
A
no
hi
ro
u
ka
no
shi
ro
i
A
White, color of that day corridor
no
hi
ro
u
ka
no
shi
ro
i
Ha
ji
me
te
mo
Beginning, ending, and this moment
Ha
ji
me
te
mo
Sa
i
go
mo
i
ma
mo
I'll engrave them all to
Sa
i
go
mo
i
ma
mo
Ma
u
ha
na
bi
ra
ni
ki
za
mi
those dancing petals
Ma
u
ha
na
bi
ra
ni
ki
za
O
ku
ru
yo
mi
and send it to you
O
ku
ru
yo
Dar-
ling
O
chi
ru
a
me
ni
u
tsu
ru
Nobody in this world knows
O
chi
ru
a
me
ni
u
tsu
ru
Fu
ta
ri
about the two of us
Fu
ta
ri
Se
ka
i
wa
da
re
mo
shi
ra
na
i
that reflected in the falling rain
Se
ka
i
wa
da
re
mo
shi
ra
na
i
A
Ko
i
wo
shi
ta
no
wa
i
tsu
ka
ra
I wonder since when I fell for you
A
ka
Ko
i
wo
shi
ta
no
wa
i
tsu
ka
ra
Na
i
ta
no
wa
na
n
do
me
ka
I wonder how many times I cried for you
Na
i
ta
no
wa
na
n
do
me
ka
Ka
zo
e
ru
to
When I tried to count,
Ka
zo
e
ru
to
Yo
ru
ga
a
ke
ru
wa
dawn already broke the night
Yo
ru
ga
a
ke
ru
wa
Ko
ma
ru
na...
Ah, so troublesome...
Ko
ma
ru
na...
Dar-
ling
Tsu
ta
e
ka
t
ta
ko
to
wa
Something that I want to convey to you
Tsu
ta
e
ka
t
ta
ko
to
wa
I
ma
mo
mu
ka
shi
mo
zut
to
Right now, that time and forever
I
ma
mo
mu
ka
shi
mo
zut
to
O
na
ji
ma
da
yo
is still the same
O
na
ji
ma
da
yo
Dar-
ling
Ma
yo
ling
wa
nu
you
a
ru
i
te
ke
ru
It's a single guidepost
Ma
yo
wa
nu
you
a
ru
i
te
ke
ru
Ta
t
ta
hi
to
tsu
no
mi
chi
shi
ru
so we won't lose our way
be
Ta
t
ta
hi
to
tsu
no
mi
chi
shi
ru
be